(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-04T23:33:08.084679",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あー
Ah--
Koyori's Kitchen
テレン！
Ta-da!
はい、ハイ！
Yes, alright!
せーの！
Ready, go!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
研究者らしい点呼！
A roll call befitting a researcher!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわーー！ 気合いの点呼！
Wahh! A spirited roll call!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
こよりの朝食はネギ！
Koyori's breakfast is green onions!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわーー！ ヘルプ！
Wahh! Help!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわーー！ インテグラル！
Wahh! Integral!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
頭脳なんでね、みゃこー！
Since I'm the brains, Myako!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
頭いいんです、テヘッ！
I'm smart, tee-hee!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
オッケー！ 告白です！ うわーー！
Okay! It's a confession! Wahh!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
ちなみにスダチは空気です！
By the way, sudachi is air!
はい、お兄ちゃん、点呼！
Alright, Onii-chan, roll call!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、そうですよね？
You always keep frozen udon stocked, right?
助手くん？
Joshu-kun?
やったー！
Yay!
証明完了 Q.E.D.！
Proof complete, Q.E.D.!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
告白だろ告白、リア充死ね！
It's a confession, right? Normies go explode!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
絵の具にはチロシンを送る！
Send tyrosine into the paint!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
大丈夫かな？ ヴイヴイヴイヴイ！
Is this okay? V-v-v-v!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
いやーーー！ 効きませんね！
No way! That doesn't work!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
思い知れ、マヨネーズ！
Taste the power of mayonnaise!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
もふもふのプログラムは解けた！
The fluffy program has been solved!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわーー！ キュート！
Wahh! Cute!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うーー！ こよりー！
Uhh! Koyori!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
ちなみにスダチは空気です！
By the way, sudachi is air!
はい、お兄ちゃん、点呼！
Alright, Onii-chan, roll call!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、そうですよね？
You always keep frozen udon stocked, right?
助手くん？
Joshu-kun?
やったー！
Yay!
私の戦闘力は53万です！
My battle power is 530,000!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
君は助手くんです！
You are Joshu-kun!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
誰の薬味少女だよ！
Who are you calling a condiment girl?!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
けど可愛いね、トッポギ！
But it's cute, Tteokbokki!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわーー！ 1550！
Wahh! 1550!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
チャクラは飲み物ではありません！
Chakra is not a beverage!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
温故知新です！ イエス！
Learning from the past! Yes!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
尻尾振っていい？ ダメです！
Can I wag my tail? Absolutely not!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
みんなの応援が一番だよ！ 右手ーー！
Everyone's support is number one! Right hand!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
ちなみにスダチは空気です！
By the way, sudachi is air!
はい、お兄ちゃん、点呼！
Alright, Onii-chan, roll call!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、そうですよね？
You always keep frozen udon stocked, right?
助手くん？
Joshu-kun?
やったー！
Yay!
せーの、告白だよーー！
Ready, go: It's a confession!
こよりだよーー！
It's Koyori!
せーの、告白です！ うわーー！
Ready, go: It's a confession! Wahh!
はい！ ハッシュタグ #こより実験中 でした！ オッケー！
Yes! That was hashtag #KoyoriJikkentyuu! Okay!
こよは頭脳です、頭脳派ですよね？
Koyo is the brains, I'm the intellectual type, right?
助手くん？
Joshu-kun?
やったー！
Yay!
Koyori's Kitchen
テレン！
Ta-da!
はい、ハイ！
Yes, alright!
せーの！
Ready, go!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
研究者らしい点呼！
A roll call befitting a researcher!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわーー！ 気合いの点呼！
Wahh! A spirited roll call!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
こよりの朝食はネギ！
Koyori's breakfast is green onions!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわーー！ ヘルプ！
Wahh! Help!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわーー！ インテグラル！
Wahh! Integral!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
頭脳なんでね、みゃこー！
Since I'm the brains, Myako!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
頭いいんです、テヘッ！
I'm smart, tee-hee!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
オッケー！ 告白です！ うわーー！
Okay! It's a confession! Wahh!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
ちなみにスダチは空気です！
By the way, sudachi is air!
はい、お兄ちゃん、点呼！
Alright, Onii-chan, roll call!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、そうですよね？
You always keep frozen udon stocked, right?
助手くん？
Joshu-kun?
やったー！
Yay!
証明完了 Q.E.D.！
Proof complete, Q.E.D.!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
告白だろ告白、リア充死ね！
It's a confession, right? Normies go explode!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
絵の具にはチロシンを送る！
Send tyrosine into the paint!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
大丈夫かな？ ヴイヴイヴイヴイ！
Is this okay? V-v-v-v!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
いやーーー！ 効きませんね！
No way! That doesn't work!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
思い知れ、マヨネーズ！
Taste the power of mayonnaise!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
もふもふのプログラムは解けた！
The fluffy program has been solved!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわーー！ キュート！
Wahh! Cute!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うーー！ こよりー！
Uhh! Koyori!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
ちなみにスダチは空気です！
By the way, sudachi is air!
はい、お兄ちゃん、点呼！
Alright, Onii-chan, roll call!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、そうですよね？
You always keep frozen udon stocked, right?
助手くん？
Joshu-kun?
やったー！
Yay!
私の戦闘力は53万です！
My battle power is 530,000!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
君は助手くんです！
You are Joshu-kun!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
誰の薬味少女だよ！
Who are you calling a condiment girl?!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
けど可愛いね、トッポギ！
But it's cute, Tteokbokki!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわーー！ 1550！
Wahh! 1550!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
チャクラは飲み物ではありません！
Chakra is not a beverage!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
温故知新です！ イエス！
Learning from the past! Yes!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
尻尾振っていい？ ダメです！
Can I wag my tail? Absolutely not!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
みんなの応援が一番だよ！ 右手ーー！
Everyone's support is number one! Right hand!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
ちなみにスダチは空気です！
By the way, sudachi is air!
はい！こにちゅ～！助手くん、冷凍うどんは常備してますか？スカッ！
Hi! Kon-nichu~! Assistant-kun, do you keep frozen udon stocked? Suka-!
やった～！せーの、こんこよ～！
Yay~! One, two, Konkoyo~!
博衣こよりだよ～！せーの、こんこよ～！
It's Hakui Koyori~! One, two, Konkoyo~!
はい、ハッシュタグ「#こよりすけっち」ありしゃ～！
Yes, thank you for using the hashtag #KoyoriSketch~!
おっけ～い！こよは頭脳派です！スカッ！
Okay~! Koyo is the brains! Suka-!
やった～！こよりすけっち、てれれん、はい、ほい！
Yay~! Koyori sketch, tereren, hai, hoi!
せーの、はい！はい！はい！
Ready, set, hai! hai! hai!
はい！研究者らしい被験体、はい！はい！はい！
Hai! A test subject fitting for a researcher, hai! hai! hai!
はい！期待の被験体、はい！はい！はい！
Hai! A promising test subject, hai! hai! hai!
はい！有料助手くんはネーム、はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Paid Assistant-kun has a name, hai! hai! hai!
はい！うわ～！てれふ～！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Uwaa~! Terefu~! Hai! hai! hai!
女のガチトーク第4回～！
Real Women's Talk, Episode 4~!
イエ～イ！やった～！
Yay~! Woohoo~!
4回だ！
It's the fourth one!
4回目です！
It's our fourth time!
そして今回もなんと、ゲストがいます！やった～！
And once again, we have a guest today! Yay~!
やった～！お邪魔してます～！いらっしゃ～い！
Yay~! Thanks for having me~! Welcome~!
と言うことで、いらっしゃいませ～！
And so, welcome to the show~!
本日はノエル先輩が遊びに来てくれました。よろしくお願いいたします～！
Today, Noel-senpai came to hang out with us. Thank you so much for joining!
よろしくお願いしま～す！
Nice to be here! / Welcome!
ほんならちょっと自己紹介がてら、今日の意気込みなど聞いてみましょうか。じゃラミィたん！
Let's do self-introductions and hear everyone's thoughts for today. First, Lamy-tan!
はい！ホロライブ5期生の顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！
Hai! I'm Hololive 5th Gen's "Liver is her Face", Yukihana Lamy!
今日もどんな相談が来てるのか楽しみです！よろしくお願いします～！
I'm really looking forward to seeing what advice people are asking for today! Nice to be here~!
お願いしま～す！
Welcome~!
そして、すのすのの頭脳のほう、博衣こよりだよ～！
And I'm the brains of Sunosuno, Hakui Koyori~!
毎回どんどんマシュマロが増えている気がします。
I feel like we're getting more and more Marshmallows every time.
お～！嬉しいことだ！
Ooh! That's wonderful!
ねえ、本当嬉しくって。あとはみんな結構ね、恋愛してるんだな～とホクホクしております。
Right? It makes me so happy. And it warms my heart knowing so many people are in love.
今日もありがとうございます！よろしくお願いしま～す！
Thank you all for today too! Let's have fun~!
お願いしま～す！
Let's do it~!
そして、ゲストのノエル先輩！どうですか、この番組？
And now for our guest, Noel-senpai! What do you think of this show?
プレッシャー！
Such pressure!
えー、皆さんこんまっする～！ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです。
Kon-muscle, everyone~! I'm Hololive 3rd Gen's Shirogane Noel.
いや、ずっとね、ちょっと興味があり、団長、こよちゃんとかにね、その...
Well, I've always been interested in it, and Danchou said to Koyo-chan and others...
「いや、あれってゲストどんな感じになってるの？」
"So, what are the guests like on that show?"
チラッ、チラッ。「いつでも空いてますよ」みたいなね。
*glance, glance* Like, "My schedule's totally open, you know."
そういう感じでちょっと構ちょムーブをしたら、なんと今回お呼びいただきました！ありがとうございます～！
After dropping subtle hints like that, they actually invited me on! Thank you so much~!
嬉しい！ありがとうございます～！
We're so glad! Thank you~!
この番組、よく言ってるんですけど、とっても人を選ぶと思っておりまして。
As we often say, we know this show isn't for everyone...
まあね、もちろん存じ上げておりますのでね。
Well, yes, of course I'm well aware of that.
この深い時間にやるのにね、ぴったりの深い番組になってるので、
Since it airs so late, it's a deep show fitting for the late hour,
「行きたい」って言ってもらえるのすごい嬉しかったんですけど、今日はよろしくお願いしま～す！
so hearing that you wanted to come made us so happy! Looking forward to today~!
お願いしま～す！
Looking forward to it~!
NGはない感じですかね？
So you don't have any off-limit topics?
いや、もちろん！NGなんてありまっせん！
Of course! There are no NGs for me!
本当に？なかったの？ないんだ！
Really? You have none? None at all!
ない！いや、まあ、ちょっとね、
None! Well... though...
皆さんの恋愛がどんな感じなのかっていうのも、それ次第なところあるけど、
depending on what kind of romance topics people bring up, that might play a part,
団長的は、あの、NGないかなって...
but for Danchou, I don't think I have any NGs...
おー！
Ooh!
やっぱこの番組、団長もちょっと見させていただいておりまして、
I've watched this show myself quite a bit,
「団長だったらこんな気持ちだな～」とかそういうの想像しながらやってたので、今のところNGは、ええ。
and I'd imagine things like, "If it were me, I'd feel this way," so as of now, NGs are, yeah...
今のところね！今日どうなるか...
As of now, right! We'll see how today goes...
今日ちょっとぶっ飛んでたら、ちょっとわかんないかも。
If things get too unhinged today, who knows.
今日もでも同じぐらいの感じかなと思いますので。はい、よろしくお願いし...
But I think today will be around the same level as usual. So yes, looking forward...
答えづらい時はね、「答えづらい」ってはっきり言ってください。よろしくお願いします。
Whenever a topic is tough to answer, please just say "That's hard to answer" plainly. Looking forward to it!
分かりました。はい、無理強いはいたしません！
Understood. Yes, we won't force you!
それでは見ていきたい...じゃあ1個目、ジャブでこれ行っていいですか？
Let's get right into it... Can we start with this one as a light jab?
ジャブというか、なんですけど。
Well, more like a light starter question...
「こよちゃんは『ノエル先輩』呼びですが、団長はもっと打ち解けて愛称呼びしてほしいな～って『マリリシャ』並みの愛称考えちゃいませんか？」ということで。
"'Koyo-chan calls her Noel-senpai, but doesn't Danchou want her to open up and use a nickname, like something on the level of Maririsha?'"
おー、いいじゃないですか。
Ooh, isn't that nice?
さっきの配信でも言ってくれていたのか？というメッセージが。
A message asking if she mentioned that during the earlier stream as well?
そうなんだよね。なんか、こよちゃんね、ずっと団長を「ノエル先輩」って呼んでくれてて。
That's right. Koyo-chan has always called me "Noel-senpai."
ちょっとそろそろね、先輩呼びじゃなくて、お近づきになりたいなっていう。
So I was thinking it might be time to drop "senpai" and get a little closer.
えー！嬉しい！いいじゃないですか～！
Ehh! I'm so happy! That sounds great~!
色々遊んでるし、なんか呼び始めたら呼べそうな気がする。
We hang out a lot, so once I start calling you that, it should come naturally!
呼び始めがね！
Starting is the key!
慣れないかもだけど、やっぱ慣れなんだよな。時間がかかりますもんね。
It might feel weird at first, but you get used to it. It just takes time.
ぜひ呼び名...なんだろうな。でも「ラミィたん」「ノエたん」なのかな？
What kind of nickname...? Maybe "Lamy-tan" and "Noe-tan"?
ラミィたん、ノエたん？ノエたん？うん。
Lamy-tan, Noe-tan? Noe-tan? Yeah.
ノエたん、ノエ...ノエ...ノエルン、ノエたん、ノエ、ノエ...
Noe-tan, Noe... Noe... Noel-un, Noe-tan, Noe, Noe...
ノエ...ノエたんかな？
Noe... Maybe Noe-tan?
あ、ノエ
Ah, Noe...
うん、ノエたん？
Yeah, Noetan?
呼びやすそう / ノエたん / ノエたんだよね
That rolls off the tongue. / Noetan. / Noetan, right?
あれ？ / ノエたんだね
Wait. / It's Noetan, yeah.
あ、ノエたんか！
Oh, it was Noetan!
ノエたんだね / ノエたん
It's Noetan, yeah. / Noetan.
イントネーションw
That intonation!
ノエたん、ノエ…じゃあ、今日はノエたんでいこうかにゃ
Noetan... So let's go with Noetan today!
じゃあ、さかのぼ… / さかのぼ…さかのぼって
Let's backtrack— / Backtracking... Backtracking,
ちょっとやっていきたいと思います、今日
I'd like to dive into these today!
やったー！嬉しいわー！ / いいですねー
Yay! I'm so happy! / Sounds great!
さらにちょっと打ち解けられそうになったところで…
Now that we've broken the ice a bit more...
これが、これが本当のジャブですね。こちら / おっ、きた
This... this is the real introductory question. Here it is! / Ooh, here it comes!
「男一人で『ちいかわ』の映画を観に行っても大丈夫でしょうか？」 / はい
"Is it okay for a guy to go see the Chiikawa movie alone?" / Yes.
「周りから白い目で見られたりしないでしょうか？ 少し不安です」
"Will people give me strange looks? I'm a bit nervous."
「でも、おっさんもセイレーンちゃんや島二郎に会いたいんです」というのが来てますよ。どうですか？
"Even so, this middle-aged guy wants to see Siren-chan and Shima Jiro." What do you think?
え、全然 / え、なんで？ ダメな理由ある？ 逆に
Not at all! / Why? Is there any reason you shouldn't? Quite the contrary!
ないない！むしろいいよね！
None at all! In fact, it's great!
だよね！ / かわいいじゃん！ / もういいじゃん！ / うん、うん
Right? / It's cute! / Totally fine! / Yeah, yeah.
いやそうなの、これこういうの結構配信でも既に言ってるんですけど
I've actually said this on stream before,
それでも悩み多きあのリスナーさんがいたので…
but there are still troubled listeners asking, so...
何も恥ずかしくないな / そうなんだ / ねえ、恥ずかしくないでしょ / うん
There's nothing embarrassing about it! / I see. / Nothing to be ashamed of, right? / Yeah.
お二人ともちいかわ映画観に行ってるもんにゃ / うん、行ってる
Both of you went to see the Chiikawa movie, right? / Yeah, we did.
いたよね、男1人のお客さん
There were solo guys in the audience, right?
もういたいたいた！ / いるいる！しかもグッズもいっぱい着けてる！
Oh, definitely! / Plenty! And wearing lots of merch, too!
わかる、わかる！ / 心あたたまるよね / 全然平気だよ
I know, right? / It warms your heart. / It's totally fine!
ね、「気にすんな」というのをお伝えするために紹介しました
Yeah, I wanted to feature this to say, "Don't worry about it at all!"
はい！
Yes!
しかもね、あの第5弾発表されたからね！ / ね！ / あ、そうですね！
Besides, they just announced the fifth round of merch! / Right! / Ah, that's true!
だから… / めじるしアクセね
So... / The umbrella charm markers, right?
より行ってほしい / ねえ、ゲットしてきてほしいですよね！
All the more reason to go. / I hope you go get them!
島二郎をゲットしてください、是非！ / はい！ぜひぜひ！
Definitely go get Shima Jiro! / Yes! Please do!
はい！それでは続いてこちら行きましょう！女の子からです / おっ！おお！
Alright, let's move on to the next one! This one's from a girl. / Ooh!
「3人は学生時代スクールメイクなどしてましたか？
"Did you three wear school makeup when you were students?
私もしたいのですがよくわからないので参考にしたいです。おすすめのコスメなどあれば聞きたい」
I want to try, but I don't know how, so I'd love some advice. Any cosmetic recommendations?"
特にね、おすすめコスメは何個か来てました、女子が / おおー、そうなんだ！
We actually got several questions asking for makeup recommendations from girls. / Oh, really?
観てくれてるみたい / 嬉しいですねー / へえー、ありがたいですね
Looks like they're watching! / That makes me happy. / Wow, we appreciate that!
してた？スクールメイク
Did you guys wear school makeup?
スクールメイク… / え？ / なんか薄メイクみたいな？ナチュラルメイク？
School makeup... / Huh? / Like light makeup? Natural makeup?
どうなんだろ？多分学校行くときにメイクなのか、
I wonder. Does it mean wearing makeup to school,
あとは学生時代にメイクってしてた？
or just wearing makeup in general as a student?
してた / いや… / してた / え？してた？！
I did. / No... / I did. / Wait, you did?!
学校行くときもしてた？
Even when going to school?
してた / ええーっ！ / すごい！
I did. / Whoa! / That's amazing!
してたけど… / え、2人はしてなかった？
I did, but... / Wait, you two didn't?
こよは学校行くときはしてなくて、
I didn't wear it to school.
あのおでかけのときにちょっと見よう見まねでしてた
I only tried imitating it a bit when going out.
ああ、なるほどなるほど
Ah, I see, I see.
ノエル先輩…ノエたんは？ / ノエたん…ノエたんはね、あの…
Noel-senpai... How about you, Noetan? / Noetan... Noetan, you see...
いや、でもどうだろ…スクールメイク、学生時代…
Well, I wonder... School makeup as a student...
高校とかってことだよね？ / あ、そうそうそう
That means high school and such, right? / Yeah, exactly.
えー、なんかね興味はあったけど、
Hmm, I was interested in it,
してなかったかな…なんか厳しかった
but I didn't really do it... The rules were strict.
ああ、学校が？ / 学校が厳しくて
Ah, your school was? / Yeah, the school was strict.
なんかしてる子はいたんよ。でも、すぐ怒られてて / あ、それは見ちゃうな…
There were girls who did it, but they'd get scolded right away. / Ah, that'd make you hesitate...
横目で見て「あ、厳しいな…じゃあまだ早いか」って思って
I'd watch from the side and think, "Ah, that's strict... Guess it's too early for me."
ああ、そんな感じだった / 正しいと思うけどな
Ah, that's how it was. / That was probably the right call, though.
校則はそれぞれあるもんね。え、おでかけの時もしてなかった？
Every school has its own rules. Did you not wear it when going out either?
お出かけの時はね、ちょっとあの見よう見真似でプチプラあるじゃんか？
When going out, you know how there's cheap makeup?
わかる！ / 400円とか500円のクリームチークとか買って、
I get that! / I'd buy like a 400 or 500-yen cream blush...
チークだけ塗ってた黒歴史がある
and I have this dark past of wearing only blush.
えっ、黒歴史？！ / 黒歴史じゃないだろw
Huh, a dark past?! / That's hardly a dark past!
いや、今思うと、やっぱさトータル大事じゃん？ / 全体のね
Looking back now, the overall balance matters, right? / The overall look, yeah.
そういうの気にせず口紅だけとかさ、チークだけっていう
Without worrying about that, I'd wear only lipstick or only blush.
なんか本当に下手くそだった思い出があるから…
I just remember being really clumsy with it,
ちょっとね、そこは恥ずかしいなって感じだけど
so thinking back on it feels a bit embarrassing.
チークオンリーはなかなか見んかもね / そうだね
Wearing only blush is definitely pretty rare! / Yeah, true.
ラミィちゃん、なんかばっちりしてそうな… / ばっちりね
Lamy-chan seems like she would've had full makeup on. / Full makeup, yeah.
ラミィはしてたね、結構コスメ好きだったから / おおー、おしゃれ！
I did wear it. I really liked cosmetics back then. / Ooh, stylish!
別に見られるわけでもなく、スクールメイクしてましたね
Not that anyone was really looking at me, but I wore school makeup.
ええー！なんかコツというかさ、スクールだったからこそみたいなやり方とかあった？
Ooh! Any tips or techniques specifically tailored for school?
ああでもやっぱアイラインめっちゃ濃く引いちゃうとさ、バレちゃうじゃん / あ、確かに！
Well, if you draw eyeliner too thick, you'll get caught. / Ah, true!
バレないようにやってたんだ / そうそう、涙袋も
So you did it so you wouldn't get caught? / Exactly. Aegyosal makeup too.
一応ね、バレないようにというか薄めに
Just to be safe, so it wouldn't be noticeable—or rather, on the subtle side.
薄めにやってた？ / うん
You kept it subtle? / Yeah.
でも なんか結構いろいろ眉とかも整えてたし
But still, I shaped my eyebrows and things like that...
ああ 確かに！
Ah, that's true!
眉ねー
Eyebrows, yeah!
大事！大事！大事だよねー
Important! They're so important, right?
そう やっぱ眉毛はね 顔の印象だいぶ変わりますからね
Right. After all, eyebrows change your facial impression so much.
うん だからだいぶナチュラルメイク CANMAKEとかも使ってたよ あのプチプラの...
Yeah, so super natural makeup. I even used CANMAKE and stuff, budget...
キャンメイク！キャンメイクですよ やっぱ
CANMAKE! It's gotta be CANMAKE, after all!
神だよね 神だねー
Total godsend, right? / Godsend!
キャンメイク今も使ってて 結構
I still use CANMAKE quite a bit even now.
可愛いしね パッケージがね
The packaging is cute too.
そう 可愛い 安い しかも結構質が高い と思っている
Yeah, it's cute, cheap, and on top of that, the quality is pretty high, I think.
めっちゃいい なんかその この価格だけどチークの塗りとかもすごい綺麗に出るし
It's so good. Like, for this price point, even the blush goes on super nicely.
そうそう なんかね コスメすごい好きなお友達がいるんですけど その子もキャンメイク結構取り入れてて
Right, right. I have a friend who's super into cosmetics, and even she uses CANMAKE a lot...
高いお金にこう固執しなくても全然素敵なメイクできるなってオススメしたかったです
So I wanted to recommend it, showing you can do wonderful makeup without fixating on expensive products.
ああ そうだね オススメだね
Ah, that's so true! / Definitely recommended.
てか今やね 結構100均とかでもさ あのメイクグッズって売ってるじゃないですか
Besides, nowadays they even sell makeup items at 100-yen shops, right?
確かに あるー
That's true, they do!
あれもなんか結構普通に使えるんよ
Those actually work pretty well too.
えっ そうなんだ！
Wait, really?!
そうそうそうそう / 使ったことなかった オススメとかある？
Right, right. / I've never used them. Do you have any recommendations?
あ でもアイライナーとかは全然発色もいいし 落ちにくいし
Ah, but eyeliners have great color payoff and don't smudge easily...
あ そうなんだ！すごっ！
Ah, really?! Amazing!
そう 全然使えるよ めっちゃいいよ
Yeah. They're totally usable. Really good.
学生だとやっぱね 高いからね メイク道具も
Since students don't have much money, makeup tools are expensive, after all.
月一ぐらいの感じになるじゃん 一個ずつ そうするとやっぱ100均嬉しいよな
You end up buying them like one per month, piece by piece. So 100-yen shops are such a blessing.
100均ね！気軽にできるしね
100-yen shops! Easy to try out.
ぜひ参考にしてみてください！
Please definitely check them out for reference!
はーい！
Okay!
はい では次ちょっと男子からね いきましょうかね 多分男子
Okay, let's move on to one from a guy next. Probably a guy.
「美女3人のフェチが知りたいです！」
"I want to know the 3 beauties' fetishes!"
うわー！フェチ！フェチ！
Whoa! Fetishes! Fetishes!
フェチかー 何フェチある？
Fetishes, huh... What fetishes do you have?
今ちょっと考えている もう考えてる
I'm thinking about it right now.
え でもねー ラミィ結構ね やっぱちょっと汗の匂いかもしれないなー
Well, for Lamy, maybe it's the smell of sweat, after all.
匂い！そう言ってた！
Smell! You mentioned that before!
そう ちょっとやっぱみんな 今さ ちょっと露出が激しいじゃないですか 今
Yeah, like everyone... right now our outfits are pretty revealing, right?
やっぱでもなんか ちょっと汗かいてそうなところの匂い嗅ぎたいもんね
I kind of want to sniff the spots that seem like they'd be sweating.
ええー？！嗅がせたくないけどな！
Ehh?! I wouldn't want to let you sniff that, though!
え 嗅がせたくないよ！汗は汗やで！
I wouldn't let you sniff! Sweat is just sweat!
そうだ これ前にももしかしたら取り扱ったかもしれない 声は声？その時も言ってた気がしますね
That's right. Maybe we covered this before. Is yours "voices"? I feel like you said that back then too.
あ 声なんだ！ / 声 やっぱなんか声優さんとか好きだったから 子供の頃から
Ah, voices! / Voices. I've loved voice actors ever since I was a kid.
「あ この人の声はこんな感じなんだなー」みたいなのちょっとまず気にしてしまうところありますね
I tend to notice things first like, "Ah, so this person's voice sounds like this."
さあ ノエル先輩！
Now then, Noel-senpai!
ノエたん ノエたんは？
Noe-tan, what about you?
ノエたん？
Noe-tan?
今おねだり出た！ノエたん！
She just begged for it! Noe-tan!
ノエたん ノエたんは...
Noe-tan... Noe-tan is...
さ 手かも！
Maybe... hands!
手？！手？！手？！
Hands?! Hands?! Hands?!
手のどういう手が良いかと言うと？
If hands, what kind of hands do you like?
え むちむちな手が好き！
Um, I love plump, squishy hands!
むち... あ 赤ちゃんみたいな？！
Squishy... Ah, like a baby's?!
そう 赤ちゃんみたいな手が好き！
Yeah, I love hands like a baby's!
へえーー！意外！
Ehh?! How unexpected!
なんか触ったら気持ちよさそうとかそういう感じ？
Like, touching them would feel nice, that kind of thing?
それもあるし なんかこう見た目的にも可愛いなと思って
That too, and visually I think they look cute.
ああー！
Ahhh!
で なんかやっぱさ 手とかって骨格とかなんか骨格でさ...
And hands, like, because of bone structure...
見た目的には全然細いのに 手だけさ ちょっとむちむちしてる女の子とかいるじゃん
Even if someone looks totally slender overall, there are girls whose hands alone are a bit squishy, right?
確かに！確かに！
Totally! Totally!
そう なんかそういう子に憧れるんだよね 団長さ... ま ちょっと今画面にはね 映ってないけど
Right! I really admire girls like that. Dancho is... well, you can't see them on screen right now, but...
手が結構やっぱり なんか骨 骨がちょっと角張ってるんだよね これがちょっとコンプレックスで
My hands are quite, like, the bones are a bit angular. I'm a little self-conscious about that.
えー そうなんだ！
Ehh, really?!
そう なんか丸みがあるお手手はずーっと憧れてるの
Yeah, I've always admired round, soft hands.
へえーー！そうなんだー！
Ehh! I see!
知らなかったー / そうなのよー
I didn't know that. / Yep, it's true.
だからクリームパンみたいな手とかもう大好き！
So I absolutely love hands that look like cream buns!
ええー！握りたくなるかもね
Ehh! You'd probably want to hold them.
そう！ / なるほどー！ / なんか今でもコメント欄に「吉良吉影」って言われてて...
Right! / I see! / Though in the comments people are calling you Kira Yoshikage...
いやいや そんな... あの 切ったりそこまでは...
No no, not like that... I don't sever them or anything...
そこまでだ！そこまでだな！
That's far enough for Hololive! Hold it right there!
怖い怖い なるほど 「ちょっと気にしちゃうな」というところですかね
Scary, scary! I see, so it's something you tend to notice, right?
そうですね もうフェチです / へえー そうなんだ なるほど
Right, definitely a fetish. / I see.
ではもう一個ちょっと... ノエル先輩に聞きたい 我々前回話してるやつなんですけど...
Then let's do one more... that I want to ask Noel-senpai... the one we discussed last time...
ノエたんにね！
Ask Noe-tan!
ノエたん あ 警察？ありがとうございますｗ
Noe-tan, ah, the police? Thank you lol
はい、こちらです。
Alright, here's the next one.
「相手に蛙化する瞬間としたらどんな瞬間ですか？よろしくお願いします」ということで
"'If you were to get the ick with someone, what kind of moment would it be? Please share your thoughts!'"
ああー、聞きたいですね。
聞きたい！
I want to hear it too!
蛙化っていうか、前回は「百年の恋も冷める」みたいなのって何？みたいな
The "frog phenomenon", or rather... Last time we talked about what makes a hundred years of love cool down,
話をしていて...
and things like that...
こよりはなんかその、店員さんとかに怒っちゃうとかがあると...
Koyori mentioned getting turned off when someone gets angry at store clerks and staff...
話してましたね。
We were talking about that, yeah.
あ、うんうん。それ、もちろん知っておりますよ。
Ah, yeah, yeah. Of course I know about that!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
見てくださってありがとうございます！
Thank you for watching our stream!
なんかありますか？
Do you have any others?
団長、その配信を見ながら「自分だったら何だろう？」って
While watching that stream, I was thinking, "What would it be for me?"
ちょっと想ってたんだけど...
and wondered about it...
うん。
Yeah.
えー、なんか... そうだな、嘘、嘘かな？ 嘘つかれたりとか...
Well... let's see, lies, maybe? Getting lied to, or...
ああー！
Ahhh~!
でも嘘もさ、色んな嘘があるじゃんか。
But you know, there are many different kinds of lies.
嘘でも、優しい嘘ならいいと思うんだけど...
Even if it's a lie, I think kind white lies are fine, but...
なんか、見栄を張るような嘘だと冷めちゃうかも。
if it's a lie just to show off, that might cool my feelings.
ああーー！
Ahhh~!
え、見栄を張るような嘘って例えば、「俺年収5000億ある」とか？
Wait, a lie to show off? Like, "My annual income is 500 billion yen"?
あ、もうそれ！ そういうことだ！
Ah, exactly that! That kind of thing!
いや、それは... それは普通にギャグだからいいんだけど...
No, that... that's obviously a joke, so it's fine, but...
あ、それはいいんだ！
Ah, so that's fine!
500... 5000億ｗ 5000億ってｗ
500... 500 billion lol 500 billion yen? lol
確かに5000億はねｗ
500 billion is definitely something else, haha.
まあ、そう、なんかちょっとした見栄...
Well, yeah, like small acts of flexing...
自分を良く見せようっていうのは...
trying to make yourself look better than you are...
ま、背伸びしたくらいだったらいいかもだけど...
Well, if it's just pushing yourself a bit, that might be okay, but...
なんかちょっと嫌、嫌かもな...
it might be kind of a turn-off for me...
それをね、嘘でやってもね、みたいな感じ...
Like, "Doing that with lies isn't great," kind of thing...
多分ね。
Probably, yeah.
団長はね、弱いところを見たい。
Danchou wants to see their vulnerable side.
ああーー！
Ahhh~!
なんかそうやって嘘をついてまで強く居よう、みたいなのはちょっと嫌だなっていう...
Going as far as lying just to try and look tough is kind of a no-go for me...
ああ、もっと弱い、本当のところを見せてほしいんだね、ノエルちゃんはね。
Ah, you want them to show their weaker, true selves, Noel-chan.
そう、団長ね、幼児化したおじさんが好きだからねｗ
Right, because Danchou loves infantized middle-aged men! lol
すごいピンポイントだな！ｗ
That's extremely specific! lol
そう、幼児化したおじさんが好きなんだ。幼児も好きだもんね？
Yeah, she likes infantized middle-aged men. And you like toddlers too, right?
違うの、なんかキャラクターで言う...「幼児も好き」って、ちょっと！ｗ
No! I mean in terms of fictional characters! "Like toddlers too", hey, wait! lol
あ、あれ、ちょっと言葉の綾でねｗ
Oops, that was just a slip of the tongue! lol
言葉の綾... 舌足らずのノエルだと思ったんですけどｗ
Figure of speech... I thought I was just being clumsy with my words lol
まあまあまあ、やっぱりその、バキっていう作品の...
Well, anyway, in the series called *Baki*...
あのドリアンっていうキャラがいるんだけど、その人がね、幼児化したおじいちゃん...
there's this character named Dorian, who becomes an infantized old man...
あ、おじいちゃんなんだ。
Ah, he's an old man!
そう。それが本当にタイプで...
Yeah, he's totally my type...
へえ〜〜！
Wowww!
だからなんか、嘘ついてほしくないな。ありのままで。
So I really don't want people to lie. Just be yourself.
この人、幼児化するんやｗ
This guy actually turns into a toddler lol
あ、調べた？ そう、これ幼児化するキャンディ求めますから。
Ah, you looked him up? Yeah, he infantizes and begs for candy.
あのムキムキのね。「僕、たくさん欲しい」って言ってる、キャンディが。
That super muscular guy! He says, "I want lots of candies!"
そうなんのよ。可愛いのよ。
Exactly! It's so cute!
「キャンディ、キャンディ」って、そうコメントで書かれてるｗ
The chat is writing "Candy, candy" everywhere lol
あ、そう。キャンディおじさんだからねｗ 幼児化おじさん。
Yeah, he's the Candy Old Man lol The infantized old guy.
「俺、キャンディとか要らねえし」とか言わないでほしいっていうことですかね。
So basically, you don't want them acting tough like, "I don't need candy or anything"?
そう、強がんないで、本当はキャンディが欲しいのに「甘いもん食えねえし」とか...
Right! Don't act tough by saying "I can't eat sweets" when you actually want candy...
言わないでいいからねｗ
You don't have to say that lol
「大丈夫、食べようね」ってねｗ
Just say, "It's okay, let's eat together," right? lol
「ありのままでいようね」って... 甘えさせてください。
"Let's stay as we are"... Please let them rely on me.
いやでも分かるわ。嘘は嫌だね。
No, but I get it. Lies really suck.
いやー、ノエたんに甘えられるの最高やんけ。
Man, getting spoiled by Noe-tan sounds amazing though.
ねえ！ 幼児化していいなら、するが？ｗ
Right?! If you're okay with infantizing, then go right ahead! lol
いいんですか？ しかもそれでアイスもらえるの最高すぎるの。
Are you sure? Plus getting ice cream on top of that is just heavenly.
ねえ、最高すぎる。お世話したい派。
Totally heavenly. I'm definitely the caretaking type.
え、じゃあちょっと、これは幼児化に入るのかという質問なんですけど...
Well then, I have a question about whether this counts as infantization...
はい。「正直、下ネタ言う男子はモテませんか？」という...
Okay: "Honestly, do guys who tell dirty jokes not get popular with girls?"
え、どのレベルの？
Wait, at what level?
え、分かんない！ それはちょっと想像と...「ここまでならオッケー」とかあったら、ぜひそこも聞きたいんですけど...
I don't know! That's up to imagination... If you have a line like "up to here is okay", I'd love to hear that too...
下ネタ... 下ネタ言う男子...
Dirty jokes... Guys who tell dirty jokes...
下ネタによらなくないかな？ ねねぐらいのだったら全然気になんないけど。
Doesn't it depend on the dirty joke? If it's at Nene's level, it wouldn't bother me at all.
小学生男子みたいな...
Like an elementary school boy...
そうそうそうそう！ いいかも。
Exactly, yes yes! That might be fine.
え、モテるかモテないかで考えると、どう思いますか？
If you look at it strictly as "popular or not popular", what do you think?
モテないんじゃない？
Probably not popular, right?
分かるｗ ちょ...ｗ
I totally agree lol Wait... lol
何ていうか、見苦しいの問題じゃない？ 女の子の前でさ、わざわざ下ネタを言わなくても良くないか？ってなる。
Isn't it an issue of looking unsightly? Like, you don't really need to go out of your way to tell dirty jokes in front of girls, right?
そやな。そうだよねー。
That's true. That's true~.
やっぱりそういう話っていうのはさ、関係値とかが大事で...
After all, for topics like that, your closeness and relationship level matter...
そこまでの関係値に行ってるってことは、もう下ネタ抜きでモテてる気がするから...
And if you've already reached that level of closeness, you're probably already well-liked without the dirty jokes...
ああーー！ 確かに確かに！
Ahhh~! That's so true, definitely!
下ネタでモテるってことは確かにはない。
Getting popular because of dirty jokes definitely doesn't happen.
逆説ねｗ 下ネタ言ってモテる、はないｗ ないかｗ ない！
It's a paradox lol "Telling dirty jokes makes you popular" does not exist lol Not a thing lol No way!
確かにない。
Definitely not.
なんか友達止まりになっちゃいそうな感じがする
It feels like you'd just end up staying as just friends.
ああーまあね。
Ah, well...
好きな男の子が下ネタめっちゃ言ってたら、でもちょっ、やっぱ嫌だな。
But if a guy I liked made dirty jokes all the time, I'd still hate it.
ああー確かに。
Ah, true.
なんかちょっと幻滅することもあるかもね、下ネタの質によっては。
It might be a bit of a turn-off, depending on the type of dirty jokes.
内容によっては。
Depending on the content.
え、でもこの質問が来るってことは、
Wait, but the fact they're asking this question...
言いながらモテたいってことなのかな？
does it mean they want to be popular while making them?
どうなんだろう？
I wonder.
「俺は下ネタを言いたいんだ！」みたいな。
"I want to make dirty jokes!" kind of thing.
欲望(笑)
Desire (laughs).
「欲望。でもそれでモテたら嬉しいな」みたいな。
"Desire. 'But I'd be happy if I still got popular anyway.'"
「言っちゃうタイプだから、このまま生きててモテるならこのままで生きるが、
"Like, 'I'm the type to blurt them out, so if I can live like this and still be popular, I will,"
これでモテないならやめようかな」みたいな。
"but if that won't make me popular, maybe I should stop.'"
どうなんだろうね。
I wonder.
いや、これちょっデカいぞ。この子が今後モテるかモテないか左右するかもしれない。
No, this is huge. It might decide whether this person is popular or not going forward.
はっきり言っとかないと。「下ネタは多分モテないぞ！」
We have to say it clearly: "Dirty jokes probably won't make you popular!"
モテないね。モテる要素がないかもね。
You won't be. There's really nothing about them that makes you popular.
確かに確かに。モテたいならちょっと控えた方が。
For sure. If you want to be popular, you'd better hold back.
男子だけの場とかでね、言って発散したりしたらいいんじゃないですかね？
Maybe just vent them when you're hanging out with only guys?
はい。
Yeah.
じゃなくてさ、ちょっ、全然関係ない話していい？
Setting that aside... can I tell a totally unrelated story?
いいよ。
Go ahead.
あのさ、この間さ、友達とねご飯に行ったんですよ。
You know, the other day, I went out for a meal with a friend.
そしたらそこの裏にいた、後ろにいた、
And sitting behind us...
男の子の4人組ぐらいがいたんですけど、
there was a group of about four guys,
えっぐい下ネタ言ってて！
and they were telling the grossest dirty jokes!
うわー！気まず！
Wow! Awkward!
もうずーっと最初から最後まで下ネタ言ってて！
They were making dirty jokes nonstop from start to finish!
マジか。
Seriously?
まあでも、こっちまで聞こえちゃうのはあれだけど、
I mean, hearing it all the way over here was awkward, but...
まあね、飲み屋の場とかね。
Well yeah, at a drinking spot and all.
男子ってやっぱそういうもんなのかね？
Are guys just like that after all?
我々は知らないじゃん、男子だけの集まりを。
We don't know what it's like when it's just guys.
みんなそう、そうなの？みんなは。
Is everyone like that? Are all of you?
聞きたいよ、コメントのみんなにね。
I want to know, asking everyone in the chat.
「TPOを弁えてくれ」って言ってる人もいるから。
Some people are saying "Read the room and mind the TPO."
聞かないであげて。
Don't eavesdrop on them.
声の大きさ大事ね。
Voice volume is important.
聞こえてきちゃったんだもん、だって！
But it was coming right into my ears!
それはね、そっちのボリュームの問題だからね。
Well, that's their issue with volume control.
「人による」「言わないよ」「学生はそうかも」
"Depends on the person," "I don't say them," "Students might be like that,"
だそうです。
they say.
あーでもそう、学生さんぽかった、ちょっと。
Ah, but yeah, they did seem like students, a bit.
ああ、なるほどな。若気の至りやね。
Ah, I see. Youthful indiscretion, huh.
ちょっと思春期なのかもだね。
Maybe they're in that adolescent phase.
そうですね。声、声より結構聞いちゃうかも。
Yeah. Rather than trying to listen, it just reached my ears.
こういう話するんだ(笑)
"So they talk about stuff like that," lol.
気になっちゃうよね。
It makes you curious.
こより女子校だったからさ、分かんないよね本当に学生の男の子たち何考えてるのか。
Koyori went to an all-girls school, so I have no idea what schoolboys actually think about.
気になっちゃうんだ。なるほど。
It makes you curious. I see.
ちなみにノエたんは、何校というか、共学・女子校どっちでしたっけ？
By the way, Noe-tan, what kind of school did you go to? Co-ed or all-girls?
えっとね、高校まで共学で、大学で女子だった。
Let's see, I was co-ed through high school, and went to a women's college.
おおー！結構珍しいタイプ。
Oh! That's a pretty rare path.
なるほど、じゃあどっちの目線も知ってるみたいな。
I see, so you know both perspectives.
そうだね。一応、まあ分かるけども、
Yeah. I sort of understand, but...
まぁでも男子も気になるね、なんか話してたら。
still, when guys are talking, you can't help but be curious.
聞きます。ね、聞いちゃいます。
I'd listen. Right? You end up listening.
はい。ではそんな共学女子校と女子校の3人、それぞれがどう思うかという、こちら。
Alright, so here's what the three of us from co-ed/all-girls and all-girls schools think!
お、なんだ？
Oh, what is it?
「3人に恋愛の2択についてお聞きしたいです。好きな人（恋愛対象）に刺激と安心、どちらを求めますか？
"I'd like to ask the three of you about a romance question. When it comes to someone you like, do you seek excitement or peace of mind?
思わせぶりな言動などで毎回ドキドキさせてくる方か、一緒にいて落ち着く自然体でいられる方、どちらを重視されるでしょうか？
Someone who constantly makes your heart race with teasing behavior, or someone who puts you at ease and lets you be yourself—which do you value more?
私は安心タイプで、好きだよとかは伝えられるのですが、ドラマのようにドキッとさせるような言動は恥ずかしくてなかなかできません。女の子はどちらの方が嬉しいですか？」
I'm the reassurance type and can say 'I love you,' but I get embarrassed and can't pull off heart-throbbing drama-like gestures. Which one makes girls happier?"
ということなので、ちょっとこれせーので「刺激」か「安心」か、どっちか答えてみたいなと思います。
With that said, let's answer on the count of three with either "excitement" or "peace of mind"!
いいよ。はい！
Sounds good. Okay!
せーの！
Ready, set, go!
安心！
Peace of mind!
おー！揃った！揃ったね！
Ooh! Unanimous! We matched!
安心が、ここは揃えましたね！その心は？ラミィたん。
We completely aligned on peace of mind! What's your reasoning, Lamy-tan?
え、刺激って、今書いてあるのは「思わせぶりな言動などで毎回ドキドキさせてくる」って書いてあるけど、
Well, "excitement"... here it says "constantly making your heart race with flirtatious behavior,"
そんな思わせぶりな言動されたら、ラミィもう困るんだけど。
but if someone acted all flirtatious and teasing like that, I'd honestly just be troubled.
「え、それ何？どういう意味？」(笑)
"Wait, what's that? What do you mean?" lol
「何？ラミィのこと好きじゃないってこと？どういうこと？何でそういうことすんの？」
"What? Does that mean you don't like Lamy? What do you mean? Why do you do that?"
そうだね(笑) 泣いちゃうよ！泣いちゃう、泣いちゃう。
Exactly (laughs). I'd cry! You'd cry, you'd cry.
絶対安心の方がいいなぁ。
Peace of mind is definitely way better.
ノエたんはどうですか？
How about you, Noe-tan?
いや、なんか人生ってさ、生きてるって大変やん。
Well, you know, living life is tough enough already.
深い(笑) それなのに刺激なんて要らんです。
Deep (laughs). On top of that, I don't need any extra excitement.
安心が欲しい。やばい、優しさが欲しいでやんすよ。
I want peace of mind. Gosh, I just crave kindness.
分かるわ、めちゃくちゃ。
I get that so much.
いや、なんかさー、こう、ずっと一緒にいるっていう前提で考えたくて...
Like, you want to think on the premise that you'll be together for the long run...
この恋愛というものを...
When it comes to romance...
あー何？それは24時間一緒にいるってこと？どういうこと？
Ah, what? Does that mean being together 24/7? What do you mean?
あ、っていうか、もうなんだろう、付き合って本当行けるならゴールのその結婚、そして生涯最後までみたいなぐらいのところまで...
Well, more like... if you start dating and can make it all the way to marriage, and stay together for life...
墓までね。
Till the grave, right?
そうそう、墓までみたいなことを考えて、恋愛というものを考えた時に...
Exactly. When you think about romance in terms of being together until the grave...
安心がもう大事すぎない？
...isn't peace of mind just the most important thing?
ずっと癒されて、安心していこう、なんかほっとする家庭でありたいと思うから...
You want to feel constantly soothed, secure, and have a relaxing home, so...
なんか別に刺激いらんなってなる。
...you end up feeling like you don't really need excitement or thrills.
まぁそうだね。長く一緒にいること考えたら...
Well, that's true. When thinking about being together for a long time...
刺激って逆にちょっと困るかもな。
...constant excitement might actually be a problem.
しかもさ、刺激を求めるってことは、刺激ってさ慣れてくじゃんか。
Besides, seeking excitement means getting used to it over time, right?
あー確かに！
Ah, that's true!
だからこの場合の刺激っつうのは、最終的にどこまでいく...
So in that case, how far would that pursuit of excitement eventually go...
なんかちょっと怖いね！
That's kind of scary!
確かに！怖い！
Definitely! Scary!
そう、長く見た時にさ、ちょっとした刺激じゃあもう...
Yeah, looking long-term, minor thrills wouldn't...
全然反応もしないみたいになっちゃいそう。
...do anything for you anymore.
SMに発展していってしまうのか...
It might even escalate into BDSM...
大丈夫そう？！そっちに行く？！
Are you okay?! It goes that far?!
なんか刺激とか最初の3回くらいまででいいんじゃないかなみたいな感じよね。
Thrills are fine for like the first three times, don't you think?
付き合う前とかにね、そういうドキドキ感があればいいんじゃない？
Having that heart-throbbing excitement before dating is enough, right?
勝手にドキドキするだろうしね。
Your heart races on its own anyway.
勝手にやめて(笑)
Stop doing it on your own!
一人でね(笑)
All by yourself!
はい、ということで多分分からないですけど、多くの女の子は安心なんじゃないかなという...
Right, so while we can't speak for everyone, most girls probably prioritize peace of mind...
はい、そうですね。
Yes, indeed.
はい。じゃあ、ちょっと恋愛とはまた別のとこなんですけれど...
Alright. Moving on to something a bit different from romance...
「脱毛しようか迷っています。(男)」
"I'm wondering if I should get hair removal. (Male)"
しろ！
Do it!
早い！早い！食い気味！
That was fast! So aggressive!
「女性から見て毛があるのとないのとでは、結構印象変わってくるのでしょうか？」
"From a woman's perspective, does having body hair vs. not make a big difference in impression?"
「しろ」なの？
You say "Do it"?
え、もう絶対ヒゲ脱毛とかした方が良くない？だって、なんかさ、毎朝毎朝さ剃ってるんでしょ？
Well, isn't getting beard hair removal definitely better? Because you have to shave every single morning, right?
まぁ確かに。うんうん。
Ah, that's true. Yeah.
だし、刃が肌に当たると刺激になって、そこが荒れちゃったりとかするわけじゃないですか。
Plus, having the razor blade hit your skin irritates it and can cause breakouts, right?
あ、そうなんだ。
Ah, is that so?
そういうの考えると、絶対ヒゲ脱毛なんてラミィが男性だったらまず真っ先にやる。
Considering all that, if Lamy were a guy, beard removal would be the absolute first thing I'd do.
確かに。
True.
あの髭を生やしたい人は別にそのまま生やしてくださいだけど、剃ってる人はね。
People who want to grow a beard can just grow it, but for those who shave...
楽になると思うけど。
...I think it would make life so much easier.
ノエちゃんはそこまでって感じ？
Noe-chan, you don't feel that strongly about it?
団長はあんまり...その...
Danchou doesn't really... Well...
ラミィはさ、その人のこと思って言ってくれてるじゃんか。あ、そういう視点があるんだって思ったけど...
Lamy is speaking out of consideration for the person. I realized that's a valid perspective, but...
団長はちょっとね、自分の好みで言うと、なんか本当にどっちでもよくて。
In terms of Danchou's personal preference, I really don't mind either way.
え、なんかさ、毛があったときにね...
Well, when someone has body hair...
やっぱ毛ってさ意味があるところに入るわけじゃん。
...hair naturally grows in places for a reason, right?
あー、守るためね。
Ah, to protect the body.
毛深い人はその分身体をなんか守んなきゃいけないのかなと思って...
I feel like hairy people just need that much more bodily protection, so...
ほう！ストーリーなんだね！
Oho! So there's a whole backstory!
ストーリー、なんかすごいクマさんみたいだなという感じで...
A backstory, like they feel kind of like a big bear...
かわいいなって。
...which I find cute.
いや、でも脱毛しようかしないかで言うならば...
But if we're talking about whether to get hair removal or not...
脱毛しようか迷ってんならした方がいいと思う。やっぱり。
...if you're on the fence about it, I think you should just do it.
女子から見て毛があった方がとかない方がとかは人それぞれだと思うけど、やっぱ自分自身だと思うな。
Whether girls prefer hair or no hair varies from person to person, but ultimately it's about what you want.
しかも脱毛って痛い！お金もかかりますし。
Besides, hair removal hurts! And it costs money, too.
だから、周りからどう見られるかよりも自分自身がやって...
So rather than worrying about how others see you...
なんかこう過ごしやすいかでやった方が後悔もないと思うので...
...it's best to do it if it makes your daily life more comfortable, without regrets.
確かにそうかも。うんうん。
That's definitely true. Yeah.
まぁね、そういう感じで。団長は？
Yeah, that's how it is. What about you, Danchou?
あれだよね、毛がある人を見て「毛があるな、嫌だな」って思うことはないよね。
Right. Seeing someone with body hair and thinking "Ugh, hair, gross," never happens.
そうだね、そんな毛深い人を見たことがないかも(笑)
True, maybe I haven't really seen super hairy people like that.
確かに道行く人でしかないから、そこで考えることはそんなないけど...
True, we only see passersby on the street so we don't think about it much, but...
その脱毛したからいいとかしてないからいいとか、そういう印象の変化っていうのはないのかなみたいな。
...whether someone removed their hair or not doesn't really change the impression I have of them.
「あ、剃る人なんだな」「あ、そのままの人なんだな」それだけって感じがする。
It's just like, "Oh, he shaves," or "Oh, he keeps it natural." That's all.
うん、なんか本当にスタイルだよね。その人の生き様というか...
Yeah, it really just comes down to personal style—or rather, their way of life...
うん、うん、うん
Yeah...
意外とであんまり気にしたことないね
Surprisingly, I've never really worried about it.
うん
Yeah.
ま、でもなんかヒゲを、そう脱毛したいと迷ってるなら、
Well, but Lamy-tan's pressure saying if you're hesitating about beard hair removal...
したほうがいいっていうラミたんの圧。
...you should just do it.
絶対だってね、困ってる層だもんね、きっとその、
Definitely, because they must be having trouble, like...
やっぱ毎回剃ったりとかね、
...having to shave every single time,
そう、肌荒れしたりとか。
and getting skin irritation.
圧倒的に自分がやっぱ脱毛して良かったと感じているから、
Because I personally felt overwhelmingly glad after getting hair removal,
あーなるほどね。
Ah, I see.
そういうのもあるかもね。
that might be part of it.
楽ちんだからなーってね。
Because it's so convenient, right?
確かにね。
Indeed.
楽ちんではあるな。うん。
It really is convenient, yeah.
意外とね、あのーすごい痛いとことか麻酔とかやれる
Surprisingly, for places that hurt a lot, you can use anesthesia and stuff...
しねー。
Yeah.
でも分かんない、顔はどうなんだろ？ヒゲってどうなんだろう？分かんないけど。
Though I don't know how it is for the face or beards.
分かんないけど。
I don't know either.
ね。
Right?
どうなんでしょうか？ま、ちょっと調べてみてもいいのではないかと思います。
How is it, I wonder? Well, I think looking into it might be a good idea.
うん。はい。
Yeah. Alright.
さあ、では続きまして、ちょっと変なのいっていいですか？
Now then, moving on, can I go with a slightly weird one?
お、いいよ。
Oh, go ahead.
夜も更けてまいりましたので、
Since it's getting late into the night...
はい。
Yes.
お風呂で異性に洗わせてもいい場所の限界を教えてください、という
"Please tell us the limit of where it's okay to let the opposite sex wash you in the bath,"
謎のマシュマロが。
is a mysterious message we received.
何それ！？
What is that?!
えぇ！？
Ehh?!
限界？
The limit?
限界！
The limit!
誰？この「異性」って。
Who is this "opposite sex"?
何者なの？
Who are they?
そうなの！なんか、え、店？彼女？どっち！？
Right?! Like, a parlor? A girlfriend? Which is it?!
この誰、誰なの？
Who is this person?
異性って誰、誰なの？
Who on earth is this opposite sex person?
分かんないけど、ど...
I don't know, but...
でも、こよは、彼女なのだとしたら、
But Koyori thinks, if it's a girlfriend,
彼女が洗いたいならどこまででもいいんじゃない？って思った。
if she wants to wash you, shouldn't anywhere be fine?
なんか、結...え、ど、どういうこと？
Wait, what do you mean?
その、こよが彼女だったなら、ラミィはどこ洗ってもいいってこと？
You mean, if Koyo were the girlfriend, Lamy could wash anywhere?
あ、違う違う違う、え、何？ラミたんが洗ってくれんの！？
Ah, no no no! Wait, what? Lamy-tan, you'd wash me?!
嬉しそう！
You look so happy!
待って、話が変わってくるんだけど！
Wait, that changes the whole story!
そうだったらっていうこと！
I said IF that were the case!
え、なんか、あのー、え、どっちだろう？えっと、こよが彼女で、
Um, like, which one is it? If Koyo were the girlfriend,
うん。
Yeah.
で、えっと...こよが、あれ？こよが彼女ちょっと難しいな。
and... huh? Koyo being the girlfriend is a bit confusing.
彼女が、「え、君の全部洗ってあげたいの」って言ってきて、
If the girlfriend says, "I want to wash all of you,"
自分もまんざらではないなら、
and you don't mind it either,
全部洗わせていいんじゃない？
shouldn't you just let her wash everything?
おー。
Ooh.
この、あの、マシュマロの人になりきってんの、今？
Are you roleplaying as the person from the message right now?
あ、そうそうそう！なりきった上で！
Ah, yes yes yes! Roleplaying as them!
なりきった上で？そういうことか！
Roleplaying as them? Ah, I see!
そうそうそうそう！
Yes yes yes yes!
え、多分でもこのマシュマロの人は、団長たちがその異性が洗うならどこまで許せる？っていう
I thought this person was asking where Danchou and the rest of us...
アレだと思って聞いてたから...
...would allow the opposite sex to wash.
あ、違う、「洗ってほしいな」っていう側？言われる側？
Ah, the side asking "I want you to wash me"? Or the one being asked?
「洗ってほしいな」！？
"I want you to wash me"?!
「洗ってほしいな」って言われる側？
The side being asked "I want you to wash me"?
この子が、彼女に対して「洗ってほしいな」って言いたいのかもしれないから、
Maybe this person wants to ask their girlfriend to wash them,
そしたら「どこまで求めていいですか？」っていうことにするじゃん。
so they're asking, "How far can I ask for?"
どういうこと！？どういうこと！？
What do you mean?! What do you mean?!
なんか、とりあえず...
Like, anyway...
自分の立ち位置が分からない！自分って誰！？
I don't understand our roles here! Who is who?!
第三者、第三者！
A third party, a third party!
この子の、この子の彼女だとして、このマシュマロ主の彼女だとして、
Suppose you're the girlfriend of the person who sent this message,
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
で、このマシュマロ主である彼ピくんが、一緒にお風呂に入ろうってことになりました。
and your boyfriend, the sender, decides to take a bath together with you.
で、この彼ピくんは、洗ってほしいっぽい、自分の体を。
And this boyfriend seems to want his body washed.
あ、のこと？はい。
Ah, that's what it is? Okay.
そうそうそう、洗ってほしいっぽくて。
Yeah yeah yeah, he seems to want to be washed.
マシュマロ主がね？
The message sender, right?
ね？
Right?
ちょっと「洗いっこしようよ」みたいな時に、
So when it's like, "Let's wash each other,"
どこまでだったらラインを越えないのか...
how far can you go without crossing the line...
凄いな、もうライン越えてると思うんだけど。
Incredible, I feel like the line has already been crossed.
越えてるかー！
Has it been crossed?!
いや、もうお風呂入ってんなら、もう...
No, if you're already in the bath together, like...
あ、もう？
Ah, already?
ない！そんな。
There are no limits!
あ、そっかー。へー。
Ah, I see. Huh.
え、でもなんか普通だったら背中までよなーって思ったりね。
Well, but normally you'd think only up to the back, right?
あー。
Ah.
背中を流す？
Washing the back?
うん、背中の洗いっこ。
Yeah, washing each other's backs.
までなら...
If it's just that...
いや、でもラミィがこよの体洗ってもいいんだったらどこまでも洗いますけどね。
No, but if Lamy is allowed to wash Koyo's body, I'll wash everywhere, though.
嘘ぉ！？
No way?!
え、何何、どこまでもね。
Wait, what? Everywhere?
いいよ、ノエたんもノエたんも、どこまでも洗うよ！
Sure, Noe-tan too, Noe-tan too, I'll wash anywhere!
ほんまに？
Really?
洗うけど。
I will, though.
え、僕が男だったらどこまでも洗ってくれるの？じゃあ...
If I were a guy, you'd wash everywhere? Then...
お願いします！
Please do!
でもさ、ラミィ、団長の体洗ってくれるって言ったけど、
Wait, but Lamy said she'd wash Danchou's body,
うん。
Yeah.
ちょっとややこしいよ、体洗うルーティンが。
the body washing routine is a bit complicated.
何、何？
What is it?
ラミィも多分、美容にね、色々やってるから、ちょっと細かいかもしれんけど...
Lamy probably does a lot of beauty stuff too, so it might be particular, but...
あ、いい、覚える覚える！
Ah, it's fine, I'll memorize it!
スクラブとか？
Like scrubs?
全部覚える！まずは泡立てるじゃん、
I'll memorize everything! First you lather up,
で、体は洗うけど、あの、大事...あるじゃんね、その下の大事なところ。
and then wash the body, but... you know, the important private parts down there.
別の石鹸で洗ってほしい。
I want you to wash that with a different soap.
優しい泡にしてるから！
I make sure to use gentle foam!
ちゃんとそうしてるから！
Because she actually does that!
めっちゃ賛成！
Totally agree!
ね！分かるでしょ？
Right! You get it, right?
ラミィも別の石鹸で洗ってる〜！
Lamy washes with a different soap too~!
ああ、そうでしょ？そういうのをちゃんとやってくれるんならいいよ。
Right? If you properly do all that, then it's fine.
あ、ラミィね！なるほどね。
Ah, Lamy's way! I see.
分かった。じゃあ全部覚えるわ。一から全部覚えるから、洗わせてもらっていい？
Got it. Then I'll learn everything from scratch, so please let me wash you!
あ、それならいいかな。うん。
Ah, in that case, maybe it's fine. Yeah.
オッケーオッケー、任せろ！
Okay, okay, leave it to me!
またラミたん、この番組やるとラミたんがいい女であることがどんどん世間にバレていくだけの...
Whenever we do this show, what a great woman Lamy-tan is just gets exposed to the world...
いや、ありがたい！
Well, I appreciate that!
いやもうこよも言ってね。何がどうとかね、全部覚えるんで。
Koyo, you tell me too, okay? What to do and how, I'll memorize it all.
こよりなんかあまり特にないから、ラミたんがやってるやつをやってもらった方が綺麗になりそう。
I don't have special preferences, so having you do what Lamy-tan does would get me cleaner.
ああ、なるほどなるほど。分かった、任せろ！
Ah, I see, I see. Got it, leave it to me!
お任せ派ね。お任せします。
The "leave it to you" type. I leave it to you!
ま、でも今ので分かったのは、女の子の体を洗いたいんだったら、女の子結構色々気にしてることあるから、
What we learned is, if you want to wash a girl's body, girls have a lot of specific preferences...
そこを気遣ってあげるといいんじゃないかっていう感じですかね？
so being considerate of that is best, right?
そうだね。それができたら120点だね。
Yeah. If you can do that, you get 120 points.
120点ですね。ちょっと面白かったんで言っちゃいました。すみません。
120 points, yep. That was funny, so I just blurted it out. Sorry!
じゃ、ちょっとノエたんだからこその恋愛相談モードに入りたいと思います！
Now then, let's move into romance consultation mode, precisely because Noel-tan is here!
はい、恋愛相談1発目、ご紹介いたしましょう！
Yes, let's introduce the first romance consultation!
「団長がいるからということでご相談させてください。」
"Since Danchou is here, please let me ask for advice."
「今、自分にはおっぺぇの大きい彼女がいます。」
"Currently, I have a girlfriend with big boobs."
「そして何を隠そう、自分は大のおっぺぇ星人であります。」
"And truth be told, I am a massive boob lover."
Win-Winじゃん。ですが、
That's a win-win! / However,
「彼女にはカッコいいところだけを見せたく、そのことについては言っておらず、
"I only want to look cool to my girlfriend, so I haven't told her...
『べ、別に興味ねぇし』みたいな態度を取ってしまいます。」
and act like, 'I-It's not like I care or anything!'"
さっきのキャンディにちょっと繋がる感じだけど。
This kind of connects to the candy topic earlier...
「このまま我慢してカッコいい自分を見せ続けるか、
"Should I endure and keep acting cool...
それとも引かれることを前提にありのまま自分をさらけ出すのがいいか、どっちがいいんでしょうか？」
or bare my true self knowing she might be turned off? Which is better?"
これ、でもノエたん決まってるでしょ、答え。
Noel-tan, surely you already know the answer to this?
ま、何ヶ月かとかね、そういうのも関係すると思うけど。
Well, how many months they've dated might matter, but...
で、でもさ、やっぱさらけ出した方がいい！
Still, it's definitely better to bare your true self!
いつまでそのカッコいい姿... いや、最初だけだよ、本当に。バレる！
How long can you keep acting cool? That only works at the start. She'll find out!
てか、なんならバレてると思う、もう！
Honestly, I think she probably already knows!
目線でバレるんじゃないかってコメントが...
The comments say she probably knows from where he looks...
どうですか？なんか感じることある？
What do you think? Have you ever noticed that?
いや、団長感じないけど、感じたそう、街中とか。
Well, Danchou doesn't notice, but I heard people do, like in town.
コメントとかでもさ、「大胸筋がデカいと目線とか気にならないっすか？」みたいな。
Comments ask that too, like "With such a huge chest, don't stares bother you?"
気になったことない。
It's never bothered me.
え、ない？！えー！ないの？！
Never?! Ehh?! Never?!
絶対コンビニの店員さんとか見ちゃうでしょ、絶対！
Convenience store clerks definitely look, absolutely!
ラミィですら毎回会ったら見てるよ！
Even Lamy looks every single time we meet!
見てるの？！
You're looking?!
そ、それはそう、見ちゃうな。うん。
W-Well, yeah, I can't help looking!
ほ〜。それ感じてないんか。
Huh~ So you don't even notice.
もしかしたらそういう感じないような子だったな、気づいてないかもしれんけど。
Maybe his girlfriend is the type who doesn't notice either, but...
でもさ、ほら、ラミィとかこよちゃんもあるからさ。感じたりする？街中で。
But Lamy and Koyo-chan have some too. Do you ever feel it out in town?
街中はないな。
Not in town, no.
でも、「あ、今なんかちょっと目線下だな」って思うことはあるかな。
But there are times I think, "Ah, their gaze dropped just now."
面と向かって話すタイミングとかがあるから。お店の人とかもね。
Because there are times when talking face-to-face, like store clerks.
こよ的には、でも「おっぺぇ星人」まで
In Koyo's opinion, suddenly claiming you're a full-on "boob lover"...
を急に言って、それで何かが起きてしまったらちょっと怖いなって。
...and causing problems would be scary. Thinking from the girl's perspective...
いきなりだと「え、もしかしておっぺぇが大きいから
...she might think, "Wait, did you only date me...
付き合ったのかな？」とか思われちゃうかも。怖いかも。
...because my boobs are big?" That could be scary.
だから本当に付き合ってどれぐらいの期間なのかプラス...
So it really depends on how long they've dated, plus...
あとはもうちょっと、徐々にだね。褒める感じで...
And doing it gradually. Bringing it up as a compliment...
難しいよな。いや、確かに...
It's tricky though. Yeah, indeed...
一気に難しくなってきた！確かに。
This suddenly got way harder! Definitely.
でも、カッコつけるのは続かないと思うんだよね。
But I don't think trying to act cool will last.
「別に興味ねぇし」は嘘になっちゃってるから。
Saying "I don't really care" is just living a lie.
もし言えるようなタイミングが来た時には、
If a good timing to tell her comes along,
「君自身が好きなことは大前提に、おっぱいも大好きだよ」みたいな。
say "Loving who you are goes without saying, but I love your boobs too!"
言うことないだろうけど...
Not that anyone would say it like that...
ま、でもなんか「べ、別に好き...」
Well, but something like, "I-It's not like I..."
「ダメーし」っていう態度はなしで
Leave out that "it's not for me" attitude...
普通に過ごせばいいのかもね なんかその
Maybe you should just act naturally, like...
わざわざね「おっぱい星人です」って宣言することは…しなくていいかな
You don't need to go out of your way to declare, "I'm a boob guy."
なんか そうね ちょっと強がってると言うかね クールぶってね
Yeah, right. He's kind of putting on a tough front, or trying to act cool.
あー そうだね うん それかも
Ah, true. Yeah, maybe that's it.
でも団長だったら嬉しいけどね ちなみに あの…
But by the way, for me, I'd actually be happy about it.
何が？おっぱい星人だったら？ / おっぱい星人 うん
What, if he's a boob guy? / If he's a boob guy, yeah.
おっぱい星人 / 確かに求められてる感じして
A boob guy. / It feels like you're truly desired, so...
うん 嬉しい
Yeah, I'd be happy.
ラミィちゃんは？ / え？ / ラミィちゃんも立派な…
What about you, Lamy-chan? / Huh? / You also have a magnificent...
え おっぱい星人？ / うん
What, a boob guy? / Yeah.
おっぱい星人 嬉しいよ
I'd be happy with a boob guy.
彼氏がおっぱい星人だったら全然「おーラミィの胸に飛んでおいでー」ってなるけど
If my boyfriend was a boob guy, I'd be like, "Come on, dive into Lamy's chest!"
この胸でこう繋ぎ止められるみたいなところもある？なんか
Do you feel like you can hold him back with your chest, in a way?
そこ？！そういうのはないけど / え ないか！ないか！なんかさ その…
That's where you go?! I don't think like that, though. / Ah, no? No! I mean...
え おっぱい その 今付き合ってるってことじゃん
Well, in this scenario, you're already dating, right?
付き合ってる上で え おっぱいまで好きなら え もう魅力×2やん みたいな
On top of dating, if he loves your boobs too, that doubles your charm!
「じゃあずっとこのまま好きで居続けてくれるな」みたいな安心感
Like the reassurance of knowing, "He'll definitely keep loving me like this forever."
いや なんかさ… / 思うのが うん
Well, you know... / What I think is...
なんかその 自分自身にとってのおっぺーはそんなに価値はあんま感じてなくて
Personally, I don't really see much value in my own boobs.
ええー？！ / 自分の？ / うん
EHHH?! / Your own? / Yeah.
え なんで？！ / それはー！
Why?! / That's—!
もったいない！ / もったいないよー！
What a waste! / Such a waste!
でも世の中にはそういうね なんか好きな人がいるっていうのは分かってるのよ やっぱり世間一般的に
But I know there are people in the world who like them, in general.
だからありがたいなみたいに思うけど
So I feel grateful for that, but...
それでなんかそういう繋ぎ止められるとか 強みだみたいな自信にはならないかも
I don't think it gives me the confidence to say it's my strength or that it can tie someone down.
なるほどね / なるほどねー
I see. / I see.
そう… ちょっと余裕がない女なのかもしれない
Right... Maybe I'm just a woman who lacks self-assurance.
こよりが？
You, Koyori?
その 自分の価値を見出したいみたいな 多分自分自身に自信がないからなのかな
Wanting to find my own worth... Maybe it's because I don't have enough self-confidence.
そういうところもでもなんか可愛いけどね 可愛いよ
Well, that part of you is really cute too, though. It's cute!
「失言」って言われてるので…
Chat is telling me that was a slip of the tongue...
「繋ぎ止められる」は失言だったみたいですね
Saying "tie him down" seems to have been a poor choice of words.
はい では続いて えっと… これちょっと答えてあげたいなという
Alright, moving on to the next one... I really want to answer this one.
「Snow Snowのお二人 そしてゲストの団長 こんばんは！」
"Good evening to the Snow Snow duo and our guest, Danchou!"
「私は現在 海外で生活しています 現地の方から好意を寄せてくれていますが」
"I am currently living abroad. A local person has shown interest in me, but..."
「私自身は数年後には日本へ帰らなければなりません」
"I myself have to return to Japan in a few years."
「そのため 悲しい思いをさせるよりも 現地でもっと素敵な方と過ごしてもらう方がいいのではと思ってしまいます」
"Because of that, rather than making them sad, I wonder if it would be better for them to be with a wonderful local person instead."
「3人の意見をお聞きしたいです」という ちょっと真面目モードですね
"I would like to hear your three opinions." It's a bit of a serious topic.
あーーー！わーーー！
Ahhh! Wowww!
これ難しいねー / 難しいね / 気持ちは分かるね
This is tough. / It is tough. / I understand how they feel.
うん そっかー
Yeah. I see...
でもなんか 正直に言ってあげてもいいのかなって思っている
But I feel like it's okay to just be honest with them.
ああ 「数年後には帰らなきゃいけないよ」って？
Ah, telling them "I have to go back in a few years"?
そう から その… やっぱり難しいと思うけど
Right. So... it's definitely going to be difficult, but...
でもなんか それでも愛してくれるなら日本に来るか みたいな
But if they still love you despite that, maybe they'll come to Japan with you!
まあ 難しいよねー どこのあれなのかも分からないけど
Well, it's difficult. We don't even know which country it is, but...
遠距離になっちゃうしねー 難しいねー
It'll turn into long-distance too. It's tough.
「ついて来いよ」って言えっていうコメントもありますけど どうでしょうか
There are comments saying "Tell them 'Follow me!'", but what do you think?
あ そう 積極的な… / うん そうね
Ah, right, proactive... / Yeah, true.
好意を寄せてくれてる人 まだ本当に こよちゃんとかも言ってたけど 「数年後には帰らなきゃいけないんだ」っていう
If they're showing interest, like Koyo-chan said, telling them, "I have to go back in a few years,"
話をした上でね 「悲しい思いさせるよりも」とかはさ 相手側のさ 気持ちだから
and after having that talk, worrying about "making them sad" is ultimately up to the other person's feelings.
自分のそういう状況を伝えた上でどうするかは 相手に委ねてもいいんじゃないかなって思ったり
So after explaining your situation, I think you could leave the decision up to them.
するかな / どう 団長？
That's what I think. / What do you think, Danchou?
うん あ 同感！なんかさ やっぱ恋愛とかそういうのってさ
Yeah, ah, I agree! You know, when it comes to romance and things like that,
ファンタジーだと思ってて だから
I've always thought of it as a fantasy. So...
なんかこう理屈じゃないんじゃないかという夢も持ってて 団長の中で
Inside my heart, I have this dream that it shouldn't just be about logic.
だからお互いのそういう気持ちで なんかこう無理難題を乗り越えていくこともあるかもなんで
So with mutual feelings like that, you might even overcome seemingly impossible hurdles together.
ちょっと気持ちを素直に行くのもいいんじゃない なんか大人になりすぎなくても
So it might be good to just follow your honest feelings, without trying to be too mature about it.
あー確かに！ / あーー！するー！ / すごい！いい言葉や！
Ah, so true! / Ahhh! Agreed! / Wow, what great words!
ね 大人になりすぎない / ええなー / うん
Right, not being too mature. / That's so nice. / Yeah.
どうだろうなーって感じです 団長は
That's how I feel about it!
同じ気持ちですね いいと思います
We feel the same way. I think that's great.
はい なんでちょっと向き合ってみてください はい 幸あれということで 続いていきましょう
Yes, so please try facing it head-on. Wishing you happiness! Alright, let's move on.
はい こちらですね えー 女子ホロリスです こんばんは！大学…
Alright, here it is: "Good evening! I'm a female Hololive listener. In college..."
大学1年の女子ホロリスです。
"I'm a first-year college student and female Holo-fan.
恋愛相談なんですけど、この前、他大学の男性と3回目のデートに行ってきました。
This is a relationship advice request. Recently, I went on a 3rd date with a guy from another college.
3回目なので、告白とか何かしらしてくれるのかなと思ったんですけど、何もありませんでした。
Since it was our third date, I thought maybe he'd confess or something, but nothing happened.
それから、私の気持ちも冷めてきてしまって、
Since then, my feelings have cooled off,
LINEとかする気にも全くなれなくて、
and I don't feel like texting on LINE at all,
このままでいいのか悩んでます。
so I'm wondering if it's okay to leave it like this.
私はどうすればいいでしょうか？助けてー！という。
'What should I do? Please help!' ...it says."
かわいいー
How cute.
Aww, so cute.
3回目のデート
A third date...
3回目、どうなんですかね？
What do you think about the third date?
どうなんだろうなぁー
I wonder...
3回目のデート...何もありませんでした。
"The third date... nothing happened."
え、これって...
Wait, does this mean...
デートということは、え、これ付き合ってるってこ...
If it's called a date, does that mean they're dating...
付き合ってない、付き合ってない
No, they're not dating.
ないけど、3回デートして...
They're not, but after going on three dates...
3回一緒に出掛けたら、もうなんか告白とかそういう感じになるのかなみたいな。
if you go out together three times, you'd expect a confession or something.
って思ってた...うん
She was expecting that, yeah.
なるほど。冷めちゃったなら、もうそれが答えって
I see. If your feelings cooled off, isn't that already the answer...
うーん...って思う。
...is what I think.
男の子が奥手すぎて、本当は女の子のこと好きなんだろうけど
Maybe the guy is just too shy, and he actually likes her,
なんか告白する勇気がなくて、っていう
but just didn't have the courage to confess...
パターンもあると...団長そっちのパターンかなって思ってるけど
That happens too... I was wondering if it's that case,
なんかコメントがさ、結構やっぱ「キープ」とかも言われてたりして
but chat comments are saying things like "He's keeping you as a backup."
ああー、それはちょっと、あれだね。
Ah... that would be rough.
むずいねー
It's tricky, isn't it?
けど、冷めちゃったなら
But if her feelings cooled down...
どうなんだろうな、なんか...
I wonder... well,
「3回目なので告白とかしてくれるかな」っていう... / ちょっと厳しいこと言うんですけど
"Since it's the 3rd time, I thought he'd confess..." / I might say something a bit harsh here, but...
ていうなんか期待をしてるのが、ちょっと
...having that kind of expectation...
なんかあの、今後のためにもそういう価値観じゃない方がいいのかなって思った感じがある
...might not be the healthiest mindset to have for future relationships, is what I felt.
ほう / というと？
Oh? / How so?
なんかその、3回目のデートでは告白するっていう決まりは全くなかったりとか
Like, there's no rule saying anyone has to confess on the third date,
結構この世の中、告白せずになあなあで付き合ったことになったみたいな人たちもいたりもするから
and in this world, there are also plenty of people who end up dating naturally without a formal confession.
その、なんだろう...絶対に起こるイベントではないので
So, you know... since it's not an event that's guaranteed to happen,
なんかその、期待してなかったら冷めなかったのかなとか、そういうのの考えで見たほうがいいのかなって思った。
I thought maybe if she hadn't had that expectation, she wouldn't have lost interest, so maybe it's worth looking at it that way.
確かに。なんか、あれやね、多分
That's true. Well, I think maybe...
その、相手が何かやってくれるみたいな、男の子が
...expecting the other person to do something—like, waiting for the guy...
その、プロポーズしてくれたりとかさ、その「付き合って」って言ったりとか
...to propose or say "let's go out" and stuff...
受身になってはいるよね、この
...she is being rather passive here.
まあ、そうだね / そうですね
Well, that's true. / Right.
女の子はね、その願望は確かに... / いや、分かるよ！ / あるよね
Girls definitely have that wish... / Oh, I totally get it! / ...right?
分かる
I get it.
だけど、でもね、やっぱり人によってはなかなか積極的な男の子じゃない子もいると思うし
However, depending on the person, not all guys are proactive,
確かにそうだね / うん
That's very true. / Yeah.
やっぱそう、付き合うってなると、そこらへん...
and when it comes to getting into a relationship, things like that...
そうだね、もう好きだったらやっぱ自分からね、動くのも
Yeah. If you like him, taking action yourself...
大事だと思うから
...is also important, I think.
そう、「どうすればいいでしょうか、助けて」とのことなので
So, since she's asking "What should I do? Please help!"...
本当に、もうこれっきりこの男の子とはいいかなってなったら連絡取らなくてもいいし
if you really feel like "I'm done with this guy," you don't have to contact him anymore,
で、まだ、え、でも本当ちょっと好きな気持ちがあるんだったら
but if you still have even a little bit of feelings for him,
やっぱ行ってみるのもいいと思うんだよね
I think it's worth giving it a shot.
なんかここで冷めちゃうのはちょっともったいないなって思うな
Losing interest right here feels like a bit of a waste.
そうね。3回目までデートに行ったんだもんね、事実。
Right. The fact is, they did go on dates up to the third time.
そう、時間を割いてね
Right, setting aside their time.
お互いね、お互いの時間を使って会ってたわけなんだから
Since both of them spent their time to meet up,
多分、向こうにも好意があることはあるんだろうね。だって3回目もデート行ったんだもんね。
he probably does have feelings for you too, since he went on a third date with you.
でも、やっぱちょっと期待しちゃったんだね
Still, she just had her hopes up, didn't she?
多分ね、そうだね / うん、多分
Probably, yeah. / Yeah, probably.
だから、まあ本当に気になってるならね、自分からどんどん行っちゃってもいいんじゃないかな？
So if you're really interested in him, wouldn't it be fine to make a move yourself?
そうですね。なんか一旦、この期待してた自分をなくして
Yeah. Maybe first let go of those expectations you had,
で、その「告白してくれなかった」っていうのも全部なくして、その子が好きかどうか
and completely set aside the fact that he didn't confess, and think about whether you actually like him or not.
っていうことを考えてみて
Think about that,
で、好きなら4回目行ってみようぜ！
and if you do like him, let's go for date number four!
誘ってみてもいいんじゃない？
Why not ask him out?
でもね、本当に気持ちが冷めちゃったんだったらもう、逆にね、無理して行くことはないし
Though if your feelings have truly cooled off completely, there's no need to force yourself to go either.
ね、そんな気がします。あとは...
Yeah, that's how I feel. Also...
無になってっていう感じなんですけど
It's like, just clear your mind, but...
人に期待していいことは1つもないので
there's never anything good that comes from expecting things from people,
これ恋愛... 恋愛でも恋愛じゃなくても
whether in romance... romance or not romance.
そうね
Right.
うん
Yeah.
なんかやっぱ何だろう、期待ってエゴなんで
I mean, expectations are really just ego,
って思うとちょっと楽になるのかな、生き方がって
so thinking that way might make going through life a bit easier.
思いがね、うんうん
Your mindset, yeah.
はい。それでは続いて
Yes. Well then, moving on...
えっと、男の子ですね
this is from a guy.
はい
Okay.
「グイグイ話しかけに来るのはどんな意図や背景を持っているのか」という
"What intentions or background does someone have when they aggressively come talk to you?"
悩み相談でございます
is the advice request.
「同じ案件作業をしてるが直接会話が少ない後輩女性
"A female junior coworker who works on the same project but rarely talks directly.
職場飲み会開催場所移動前に後輩女性から『今日飲み会出席ですよね？
Before moving to the workplace drinking party, she said, 'You're attending today's party, right?
よく食べるとお聞きしたので、飲ませても大丈夫ですよね？』みたいなジャブな会話が来る
I heard you eat a lot, so it's okay to make you drink, right?' like a jab.
偶然にも座席の升席が同じ場所
Coincidentally, we ended up in the same seating section.
自分のコミュニケーションは高めと自負しているが、突如迫られると押し込まれるタイプ
I pride myself on good communication skills, but I get overwhelmed when approached suddenly.
何かあるのではと背景を見つつ、さりげない会話で終了
Wondering if there was something to it, it ended with casual conversation.
その後特に進展なし
No particular progress since then.
今の御時世何があるかわからないという建前を置くチキン野郎です。年齢は30代前半です」という
I'm a chicken hiding behind the excuse of 'in this day and age.' I'm in my early 30s."
ああー
Ahh...
ま、こういう行動をとる女の子... もし自分がこの後輩女子だとしたら
Well, a girl acting like this... If I were this female junior,
「どうなのかな？」みたいな妄想ですね
it's daydreaming like, "What could this mean?"
ええー
Ehhh...
あ、これはなんかあれか、相手が好意を持ってるとかそういうのじゃなくて
Ah, is this not about whether she has feelings or anything,
なんでこういう...
but why she would...
どんな意図や背景を持っているんでしょうかと
"What intentions or background does she have?"
要するにおそらく、あの
In short, probably...
この行動してくるって自分のこと好きなの？っていうのを
"Does her acting like this mean she likes me?"
女子ってどうなの？って聞きたいんだと思う
He wants to ask girls what they think about that.
ああー なるほどー
Ahh, I see.
でもあれだよね、実際に向こうからのアクションとしては
But really, in terms of actual action from her side...
あの「今日飲み会来ますよね？いっぱい飲めますよね？」って言われたこと...
...it was just being told, "You're coming to the drinking party today, right? You can drink a lot, right?"
だけだよね？
That was all, right?
確かに今書いてある内容だとそれだけかも
Indeed, based on what's written here, that might be all.
うん
Yeah.
そう、同じ升席とかはあったけど
Right, being in the same seating section happened, but...
うんうんうんうん
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
そんなに何にもなくても聞くかな？みたいな内容って感じ？
Like, would you ask that even if there's nothing behind it?
まあ... なんかこう、飲み会に行くっていうさ、きっかけっていうかあるから
Well, there's the occasion of going to a drinking party,
とりあえず飲み会前でちょっとテンション...
so to get hyped before the party...
飲み会ってさ、テンションが上がるものか分からないけど、飲み会でテンション上がって
I don't know if drinking parties get you hyped, but getting hyped for it...
で、なんか、ま、話しかけたぐらいな感じなのかなあ
...and then just striking up a conversation, maybe?
うんうんうん。っていう感じだよね、なんか本当に
Yeah, yeah. It really feels like that.
まあそうだね。でも内容としては「グイグイ話しかけに来る」っていうことも別であったのかどうなのか
Yeah. But regarding what's written, did "coming to talk aggressively" happen on other occasions too?
ああ、確かに。回数の問題はあるかもね
Ah, true. It might be a matter of frequency.
うん
Yeah.
うーん、なんかコメ欄は「何もないぞ、安心しろ」で一致しているみたいなんですけど
Hmm, the comment section seems united with "There's nothing, rest assured," though.
え、でもなんか、もしすごい「え、そんなに俺にだけ話しかけに来る？」みたいな
But what if it's like, "Wait, why does she come talk only to me like that?"
みんなにさ、同じように...
Like, to everyone equally...
飲み会の人数が増やしたくてみんなに言ってる可能性もあるかな
There's a chance she's telling everyone because she wants more people at the party.
でも自分にばっかりいろんなこと聞いてくるなってもし思うのであれば
But if he feels she only asks him all kinds of things,
なんか聞いてもいいのかなって思っちゃった
I felt like he could just ask her.
何を？
Ask what?
「そんなに、なんか俺のこと気にしてくれてんの？」みたいな
Like, "Are you really that interested in me?"
ちょっと軽く。そんなグイグイ来てるなら、こっちも軽く...
Just lightly. If she's pushing that hard, then lightly on this side too...
ジャブ打つ？
Throw a jab?
ジャブ打つ
Throw a jab.
ジャブ... いや、昨今... え？
A jab... No, these days... Eh?
昨今、コンプラが...
These days, compliance...
昨今、コンプラがね！
These days, compliance, right!
ムズいんだよね、その...
It's tricky, that...
この方も心配してるしね、ちょっと
This person is worried about that too.
そうなんだよね、すごい慎重派な方なんで
Right, he's very cautious.
だからもう本当に何だろう... グイグイ系だったら、なんか昨今ね、結構去るらしく...
So really, what is it... if he's aggressive, these days apparently people get fired...
やばい、こより駄目そうだわ、コンプライアンス
Oh no, Koyori might not survive compliance.
こよちゃん男の子でこういう悩める子羊だったらちょっとやばかったかもね
If Koyo-chan were a guy and a lost lamb agonizing over this, it might have been bad.
やばかったかも。女でよかったな、ギリギリ
Might have been bad. Glad I'm a girl, barely!
そう、なんかグイグイ、まだね、情報も薄いしってことは
Yeah, since the info is still sparse,
そんなに他でグイグイエピソードが揃ってないってことだから
it means there aren't many other aggressive episodes to go on...
一旦普通になんか仕事続けて
...so for now, just continue working normally...
会話やってでいい気がするな
...and having conversations, I feel that's fine.
そうですね
That's true.
うん、そうだね
Yeah, that's right.
ただそんな、あの、意識...
Just don't be so overly conscious...
して、多分、結構色んな人に話しかけるタイプの女性だったんじゃなかろうかという
So maybe she was just the type of woman who talks to a lot of people...
うん、性格な感じかも。だな？
Yeah, it might just be her personality, right?
あれだね、二人でご飯行きましょうとか言われたら、もう1回考えてみたいな...
If she says, "Let's go eat together, just the two of us," maybe think about it then...
あ、そうだね。感じかもね。
Ah, that's true. That might be the time.
はい、ということで。
Yes! So there you have it.
はい！はい！
Yes!
じゃ、ちょっとあと2通読んでもいいですか？
Alright, can I read two more letters?
もちろんですよ！ / はい、どうぞどうぞ。
Of course! / Yes, go ahead!
女の子と男の子それぞれ行こうと思うんですけれど...
I'd like to do one from a girl and one from a boy...
可愛い奴です！学生の女子隊員です！
It's a really cute one! From a student girl member!
おお、隊員さん！ / あら、隊員さん！
Oh, a member! / Oh my, a member!
「今、絶賛片思い中なのですが...」
"I'm currently in the middle of a big crush..."
「どうすれば相手に振り向いてもらえますか？」
"...how can I get him to notice me?"
「モテる行動とかヘアスタイルを教えてほしいです。」
"Please tell me what actions or hairstyles are charming."
「ちなみにユニバのアトラクション、二人で乗ったことあります。♡」
"By the way, we've ridden an attraction at USJ just the two of us. ♡"
幸せかー！
Are you happy or what?!
可愛いー！
So cute!
はい、優勝！ / 優勝！
Alright, you win! / Winner!
可愛いー！
So cute!
くーっ、可愛い！ / 可愛いですね。 / 可愛いね。
Aww, so cute! / That's so cute. / So cute.
どうですか？モテる行動とかヘアスタイル教えてほしいって。
What do you think? She wants to know charming actions or hairstyles.
え、でもさ、その好きな男の子がさ、どんなスタイルが好きなのかにもよるくない？
Well, doesn't it depend on what style the boy she likes is into?
いや、そうなんだよねー！ / そう！
Right, exactly! / Yeah!
確かにね。 / これはねー。
True. / That's the thing.
あと、この子に似合うとかも大事だったりするしなー。うーん...
And what suits her is also really important, so... hmm...
まあでも、本当に一つだけ言えるのは、もうすでに可愛い！もう恋してる女の子、可愛いよ！
Well, one thing I can definitely say is she's already cute! A girl in love is just adorable!
うん、可愛い！ / 可愛い。可愛い。
Yeah, so cute! / Cute, so cute.
もう、いっぱい、いっぱい笑ってね。そう、笑う女の子が、もう最高やから！
Just smile and laugh lots and lots! A smiling girl is truly the best!
あ、確かに！ / 愛嬌だよ、愛嬌！ / 愛嬌、本当！
Ah, definitely! / It's all about charm! Charm! / Charm, really!
「男は度胸、女は愛嬌」
"Men need courage, women need charm."
ということですね？ / 昔から言うよね！ / 昔から言うよね。
Is that what it is? / That's the old saying, right? / An old saying.
いや、でも大事だと思うよ。笑顔をよく、「俺の前だとすごい人一倍この子笑ってくれるな」とかさ。
No, but I really think it's important. Smiling a lot, so he thinks, "She laughs around me way more than anyone else."
確かに！絶対キュンとくるポイントでしょ！ / そうだね、本当。
Definitely! That's guaranteed to make his heart flutter! / Totally true.
なんかこのさ...うん。なんか「幸せ」って思ってるやつを...
Like, this... yeah. Feeling that "I'm so happy" vibe...
...もうなんか伝わるぐらいニコニコしまくり、話しかけたりとかしてもいいのかなって。
...and smiling so much that it clearly conveys it while talking to him, might be great.
そうだねー！と思っちゃいます。
That's so true! That's what I think.
はい。大事、大事。 / いや、本当そうだなぁ。
Yes. Very important. / Yeah, really true.
うん。もう自信持って、すでに可愛いので。あとはあれかもね、なんかさ...
Yeah. Have confidence, you're already cute! Also maybe...
...もしヘアスタイルとか変えたいならさ、「好きな女の子の髪型とかあるの？」って聞いて...
...if you want to change your hairstyle, ask him, "Do you have a hairstyle you like on girls?"...
次の日それをやってくる！涼宮ハルヒですよ！
...and wear it the next day! Just like Haruhi Suzumiya!
「あ、めっちゃ意識してるじゃーん！」って！ / 「俺の事を！」
"Ah, you're so totally into me!" like that! / "Into me!"
え、そういうのどう思う？
What do you think of doing that?
え、可愛くない？！ / 良い！ / よね？！
Isn't that super cute?! / Great! / Right?!
可愛い！ / 可愛い！ね、可愛いよねー！
Cute! / Cute! Right, so cute!
そういうのやってみちゃってもね、いいかもしれないなって思います！
I think trying something like that might be really good!
良いと思います！ / それやってなんか変な感じになったらどうしようって、今ちょっとソワソワしてるんですけど。
I think it's great! / Though I'm feeling a bit restless now wondering what if it gets awkward if she tries it.
責任は負えないなー！
Can't take responsibility for that, though!
まあまあまあね、相手の男の子がどういう感じなのかわかんないからね！
Well, well, we don't know what kind of guy he is, after all!
ねー。でも可愛いでしょう。
Yeah. But it would be cute, right?
うん、可愛いよなぁ。 / してほしいですね！はい。
Yeah, definitely cute. / We'd love to see you try it! Yes.
それじゃあ、えー、ラストは男子からの行こうかなと思いますけれども...
Now then, for the last one, I think I'll go with one from a guy...
えーっと、どっちにしようか。
Let's see, which one should I pick...
ほんとに、もうホクホクしてる。
Seriously, my heart is so warm.
うん、ホクホク。ほんとね、恋愛、楽しいよね、人の恋愛をこう感じるだけで。 / そうだね。
Yeah, so warm. Hearing about other people's romance is just so fun, isn't it? / True.
じゃあこちらですね。やっぱりちょっとノエル先輩ということで、ちょうど、あ、ノエたんということでね、ちょっとそういう奴ですね。 / あ、ノエたんだね！ / はい。
Then let's go with this one. Since we have Noel-senpai—or rather, Noe-tan—here with us today, this kind of submission. / Ah, Noe-tan! / Yes.
「大人の女性ならではの魅力をお持ちの、すのすの＆ノエたんさんに質問です！」
"A question for Suno-Suno and Noe-tan, who possess the unique charm of mature women!"
「私はいつか、素敵なお姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いをして、お互いに支え合えるような関係を築きたいと思っています。」
"Someday, I want to date a wonderful older-sister type woman and build a relationship where we support each other."
「そこで質問なのですが、お姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いするための秘訣や、こういう男性だといいなと思うポイントなどはありますでしょうか？」
"So my question is, what is the secret to dating an older-sister type woman, or what traits make a man appealing to them?"
「ぜひお二人の（3人ですね）意見やアドバイスを聞かせていただけると嬉しいです！」という。
"I would love to hear your (all three of you!) opinions and advice!"
あら、あら。 / あら、あら。大人の女性、あら、あら。
Oh my, oh my. / Oh my, oh my. Mature women, oh my, oh my.
あら、あら。大人のお姉さんに憧れている。 / ホロライブのあら、あら。
Oh my, oh my. Yearning for a mature older sister. / The "Ara, ara" of Hololive.
はい。「お姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いするための秘訣」
Yes. "The secret to dating an older-sister type woman."
これどうですか？ / お姉さんもね、いろんなタイプがいるからねー。
What do you think? / There are lots of different types of older sisters, after all.
ま、じゃあノエたんタイプのお姉さん...こう優しい、ほんわかしたお姉さんと付き合うには...
Well then, for a Noe-tan type older sister... a gentle, warm-hearted older sister, to date her...
うん
Yeah.
あり... えー
That could work... Hmm.
え、でも、うん。
Well, but, yeah...
そうだな、なんか普通に
Let's see... I think just normally,
変にさ、背伸びしなくていいと
without unnecessarily trying to act mature,
思ってて――
you don't need to...
一貫してるね
You're being really consistent.
そうだな
Yeah.
そう、なんか本当に、こう真面目に生きて、
Yeah, like, living earnestly,
なんか精一杯、精一杯で頑張ってるところとかを、
giving it your absolute all and working hard...
なんか結構、あれなんじゃないかな。
I think that's what really matters.
そう、せ... なんて...
Yeah, like... how to put it...
感じがちょっと難しいな。自分がさ、お姉さん...
It's a bit hard. Since I'm wondering if I'm even...
お姉さんタイプでいいのかって思いながら...
the "older sister" type in the first place...
お姉さんだよ！お姉さん！
You are! You're an older sister!
お姉さん、お姉さん。甘やかしてくれそうっていうのが、
Definitely an older sister. The feeling that you'd pamper someone...
なんかお姉さん感。 そうだね。
has that big sister vibe. / True.
なんか本当に、精一杯、精一杯頑張ってる姿とか、
Just seeing someone trying their hardest and giving their all...
が、ま、それはさ、お姉さんとか関係なく人として、
though setting aside the whole "older sister" thing, as a person,
なんか素晴らしいと思うからさ、
I think that's truly wonderful.
なんかそんな感じかな。
So I guess that's how it is.
特にこういう、こういう所がいいみたいなさ、
I'm sorry I can't pinpoint...
ピンポイントでちょっと言えなくて申し訳ないけど、
specific things like "I like this exact trait,"
ま、一生懸命...
but trying your best...
一生懸命なんか生きてる人は、
People who live their lives giving it their best,
すごい魅力的だなって思う。そういう人を甘やかしたいなって思う。
I find them really attractive. And I'd want to pamper someone like that.
「今日もお仕事頑張ったー！」
"I worked hard today too!"
「よしよしよし！」「ママ～！ママ～！」
"There, there, there!" / "Mommy! Mommy!"
「褒めて褒めて～！」
"Praise me, praise me!"
ということですかね？
So is that what it's like?
ってやっていいってことですよね？ うーん...
Like, doing that is okay, right? / Well...
え、でもちょっと重いんですけど、お姉さんに好かれるってバブみとかさ、
Thinking about it, being liked by older women is associated with babying...
甘えるタイプがやっぱりお姉さんに好かれるのかな、みたいな...
like you have this image that older sisters prefer clingy types...
二次元脳というか、イメージがあるじゃないですか。
like having an anime-style preconception.
だからと言って、バブバブーで生きる...
But even so, acting like a complete baby...
ではないよなって思うんですけど、どうでしょうか？
isn't really the way to go, right? What do you think?
いや... バブバブは...
Well... Going full baby...
バブバブ駄目ですか？
Is baby mode not allowed?
いや、なんかそれもそれで可愛くてあり...
No, that's cute in its own way, so it could work...
あ、そうなんだ！ 包容力がある...
Oh, really?! / That's some serious maternal embrace...
いや、あり、ありだな。だから本当に難しい。
Yeah, it totally works. That's why it's so tricky.
そう、なんかこういうことを言って、こう戦略だと、
Yeah, talking about it as a strategy,
思ってて、その、マロ主さんがどういうタイプ...
it really depends on what type the sender is...
こういうのってさ、あの、
Because in these situations,
なんか善し悪しじゃなくて、その、
it's not about good or bad,
タイプってあるじゃん。そう、自分は、
it's about your own style. Like, for example,
例えば背が高いから、そういうかっこいい系でスタイリングしてるとか、
if you're tall, you might style yourself in a cool way,
逆に、いや自分は結構童顔って言われるから幼い感じで、とか。
or if people tell you that you have a baby face, you go for a youthful look.
なんかそういう、なんか戦略？
Finding that kind of strategy,
やっぱ自分にあった感じとかも大事かな。
matching what suits you best is important.
あと性格とかも。
And your personality too.
だから、なんだろうな。
So, I wonder...
どのタイプでも普通にお姉さんに好かれそうな気がする。
I feel like any type could naturally be liked by older women.
精一杯に背伸びしてるタイプも、バブバブなタイプも。
Whether it's trying hard to act mature, or being a baby.
逆に、なんか本当にNGなようなことをしなければ、
On the flip side, as long as you don't do anything that's a clear dealbreaker,
なんかいいなーって...
I think it's fine...
清潔感！清潔感ですね！
Cleanliness! Personal grooming!
もうこれあれだね、お姉さんとか関係なく、
At this point, it has nothing to do with older women—
人に好かれるということ、みたいな感じですかね？
it's just about being liked as a person in general, right?
難しいし、本当になんか... いやムズいね。
It's tricky, honestly... Yeah, it's really tough.
こちら難しいんだけど。
This is a tough question.
ま、人にもよるからみたいなところはあるよね。
Well, it does depend on the person.
ラミィちゃんお姉さんとしたら、どうですか？
If you look at it from your perspective as an older sister, Lamy-chan?
ラミィお姉さん属性ある？
Does Lamy have the older sister trait?
ま、あんまないかも...
Well, maybe not much...
あるある！ あるよ、あるよ！
She does! / I do, I do!
でもみんなお姉さんっぽいて言ってるから、この人は。
But the sender says everyone sees you as an older sister type.
おー、そうなんだ。ラミィにお姉さん属性...
Oh, really. Older sister trait for me...
いや、でも、
Well, but...
やっぱお姉さんあんま関係ないかもな。人としてになっちゃうな。
maybe "older sister" doesn't matter much. It just comes down to being a person.
ま、そうだね。
Yeah, that's true.
ラミィは、尊敬できる人が魅力的に見えるから、
For me, I find people I can respect attractive,
お仕事を頑張ってるとか、
so seeing someone working hard at their job,
好きなことを追っかけてるとか、
or pursuing what they love...
そういうところに魅力を感じるかな。
that's the kind of thing I find charming.
なるほどな。
I see.
だからやっぱあれかね、誠実に生きる？
So I guess it's about living sincerely, then?
もうお姉さんとかを1回置いといて。
Setting the whole "older sister" thing aside for a moment.
え、こよりは？こよりはどうなの？
What about you, Koyori? What do you think?
ま、確かに「お姉さんなのか？」っていう感じではあるんだけど、
Well, while I also wonder if I'm even an "older sister" type,
やっぱり支え合えるような関係を築きたいって言ってるから、
since they said they want to build a mutually supportive relationship,
それを大事にしていくことなのかなと思いますね。で、
I think cherishing that is what matters most. And,
お姉さんタイプの女性にとって...
for women who are the older sister type...
で、決めつけなくていいのかなと思っていて
So I feel like they shouldn't just make assumptions.
なんか、好きになった人がお姉さんだったなら、お姉さんだし、
Like, if the person they fell for happens to be an older woman, then that's that,
もしかしたら全然お姉さんじゃない人を好きになるかもしれないから、この人自身も。
but they might also fall for someone who isn't older at all.
なんかその時に、なんか「お姉さんじゃないな」ってならないで、
So when that happens, instead of thinking, "Wait, she's not an older woman,"
好きになったなら、その好きになった人と幸せになってほしいなって思いました。
if they've fallen in love, I'd want them to just find happiness with that person.
そう、うん。
Yeah, absolutely.
からもう... 幸あれ。
So basically... May happiness be with you!
幸あれ、なんですね。
Wishing them bliss, then.
で、なんかね、ちょっとね、一個、今の話の流れでですね、
And you know, following up on that conversation,
ちょっと悩んでた人がいるんで、一個だけちょっと没枠で行くんですけども...
someone sent in a worry, so let me quickly bring up one rejected submission...
ぜひぜひ！ / はい、はい。
Go right ahead! / Sure, sure.
質問です！女性から見て恋愛や結婚に前のめりにならず、
"Question! From a woman's perspective,
自分のやりたいことに挑戦や目標に向けての行動を最優先にして取り組んでいる男性ってどう思いますか？
how do you view men who prioritize pursuing their goals and dreams over dating or marriage?"
っていうのがあったんですよ！
That was the question!
うえっ / ええやん！
Sounds great!
これは何？えっと...つ、付き合ってる彼女がいてってこと？
What does this mean? Like... they already have a girlfriend?
多分そういうことではなく、自分自身が恋愛とか結婚とか多分何にも興味なく、
Probably not that, but rather they themselves have no interest in dating or marriage,
あの、仕事に一生懸命なんだと思うの。
and are just totally devoted to their work.
今でもさ、仕事に一生懸命な人って素敵みたいな話が、あったやん。
Earlier, we were saying how wonderful someone devoted to their work is, right?
「どう、どう思いますか？」っていうのは、
So asking "How do you view them?"
なんか恋愛対象になるかな、みたいな話でもちょっと考えてみるといいのかな。
probably means wondering if they could be seen as a romantic partner.
いやもう、え、もう良さしかなくて、今ちょっと、あれなんですけど...
Man, I only see good things about that, so it's a bit hard to critique, but...
なんだろうな。なんか...団長的に、こう個人的にね、思うのが、
What should I say? Personally, from Danchou's perspective,
いやめちゃめちゃやっぱさ、尊敬できるからさ、「すごいな」って思う反面、
you can really respect someone like that and think "That's amazing," but on the flip side...
ただ...「隙がない」と思うのよ。
However... you feel like they have "no openings."
ああー！確かに、確かに。
Ah! True, so true.
もしかして近寄りがたいみたいな。
Like they might be hard to approach.
そういうところはちょっと、ある。なんか...
There is a bit of that. Like...
多分、恋愛とかってさ、お互いのその歩み寄りだったり、その歩幅とかが...
in romance, when compromising or matching each other's pace...
ちょっと違いすぎると、なんか破綻しちゃうと思うから、
if the differences are too big, things tend to fall apart.
多分このマロ主さんはすごい良いなって団長は思ったのって、
The reason Danchou thought this submitter sounds great
きっと団長もね、今こうやってホロライブでさ、活動すごい頑張っててさ、
is because I'm also working super hard with my Hololive activities right now,
お仕事に...ふふ、こよちゃんが...「うわあ」ってなってるけど...
and with work... Koyori's over there grinning, but...
で、仕事にこう一筋みたいなところがあるから、なんか「同志だ」みたいな気持ちで思ったんだけど、
because I'm single-minded about work too, I felt like, "Hey, a comrade!"
ただ、やっぱその恋愛とか結婚とかしたい子からすると、
But to someone who actually wants romance or marriage,
ちょっとあれかも、隙がなくて近寄りがたいっていうのはあるかもなーって思ったんです。
having no openings might make you feel unapproachable, is what I thought.
素晴らしいです！
That is wonderful!
拍手出てきた！
She's even clapping!
いや、こよの顔ずっとニコニコやったよ。
Koyori's face had a huge grin the whole time.
ニコニコというか、なんかこれね、すごい素敵じゃん。
Rather than grinning, I just thought, this question is so wonderful.
その2人のさっき話した内容も含めて、「すごい素敵やん！」ってなるなと思ったの。
Combined with what you two talked about earlier, it made me think, "How great!"
で、でもこよりは一個この子に伝えたいなって思ったことがあって、
But there was one thing Koyori wanted to tell this person,
それはすごく素敵なことだし、とっても人間として素敵なんだけど、
which is that while it's wonderful and makes them an admirable person,
その生活をずっと続けてると、
if you keep living that way forever...
「何も起きないぞ、気をつけろ」って...
"Nothing will ever happen, so be careful!"
こよりからの！ / そう！
Advice from Koyori! / Right!
って、なんか言うだけは言ってあげたいなって思ったのね。
I just wanted to give them that one heads-up, you know?
で、それを言って締めようかなぐらいに思って今これを取り上げたんですけど、
I brought this up intending to wrap it up with that punchline,
その理由がもうノエたんの口から全部出たから、すごい拍手でした。
but Noe-tan laid out all the reasoning already, so I just had to applaud!
ああ、なるほどね！
Ah, I see!
解決策が出たと思って、
Since a solution came up,
なんかその生活をしつつちょっと隙を...隙というものを、やっぱ結婚とか恋愛とかしたいなと思ったら、
while living like that, if they ever decide they want romance or marriage...
隙が必要なんですかね、多分ね。
they probably need to show some openings, right?
隙って何ですか？ / そうだね。
What counts as an "opening"? / Well...
え？ / いや隙ってやっぱあれなんじゃ...なんかさ、
Huh? / Well, wouldn't an opening be... you know,
多分忙しそうにしてると、やっぱり「忙しいんだな」みたいな。
if you always look busy, people will just assume you're busy.
じゃあ、多分遊ぶ時間もないんだろうな、とかさ。
And then think, "They probably don't have time to hang out."
そういうの思われちゃいそうだから。普通に趣味も楽しんでますよ、みたいな。
Since they might assume that, showing that you enjoy hobbies in daily life,
あー、いいね、いいね！ / 仕事だけじゃなくて。
Ah, nice, nice! / instead of just working.
趣味を楽しんでるってことで、「あ、時間もちょっと余裕があって...」
By showing you enjoy hobbies, people realize, "Oh, they have some free time..."
「そういうのあるのかな」とか。そういうところかな？
"...and room to breathe." Maybe something like that?
なんか、まあね、こう大々的にその「恋愛とかちょっと興味あります」とかアピールできればいいけど、
I mean, it'd be fine if you could openly advertise, "I'm interested in romance,"
それってやりすぎるとちょっと逆にね、あれになっちゃうから。本当にそういう隙？
but coming on too strong can backfire. So real openings like that,
趣味とか余裕とかかなって。
having hobbies and free time, might be it.
そこに隙を感じるってことですね。
So that's where people sense an opening.
こよりが今学んでる！学んでる！
Koyori is learning right now! She's learning!
なるほどねー
I see.
隙じゃないからね
That's not an opening, after all.
こよりがさ、ちょっとこよりが言えない、答えられない質問だからさ、これさ
Because this was a question that I couldn't really answer...
うん。
Yeah.
だから、その、ありがたいなと思って、答えてもらえて。
So I'm really grateful that you answered it.
なるほどね。
I see.
ラミたんが女の子として好きだと感じるのは、他に何かあったりする？
Is there anything else that makes you feel attracted to someone from a girl's perspective, Lamy-tan?
えー、でもやっぱ趣味は大きいんじゃない？
Well, but hobbies are pretty significant, right?
うん、やっぱそうだよね。
Yeah, that's true.
でもさ、この方さ、自分のやりたいことに挑戦してるって書いてあるからさ。
Though this person wrote that they're taking on challenges in what they want to do,
ま、お仕事だけでなくって、自分のやりたいこともできてるってことでしょ？
so it means they're pursuing what they want to do outside of work too, right?
うん、多分多分。
Yeah, probably.
すごくいいと思うけどね。めちゃくちゃ素敵だと思いますよ。
I think that's really great. I think it's wonderful.
素晴らしい。
Wonderful.
じゃあさ、あのさ、この人多分まだ好きな人とかいるわけじゃないと思うんだけど、
Well, I think this person probably doesn't have someone they like yet, but...
その、趣味を満喫してそうな雰囲気を出すのに、なんかちょっとストラップとかつけてみるとか、
to give off the vibe that they're really enjoying their hobby, maybe putting on a strap or something...
例えばさ、我々のようなちいかわ好きとかだったら、ちいかわのキーホルダーつけてたりすると、
For example, if they like Chiikawa like us, and attach a Chiikawa keychain...
「あ、ちいかわの推し活したりしてるのかな？」みたいなところから、
"Ah, I wonder if they're a fan of Chiikawa?" From something like that...
会話が生まれたりとかね。
...a conversation might start up.
そういうのどうですかね？何もつけてないとかだったら。
What do you think about that? If they don't have anything attached right now.
なんか、まあ、その仕事とかね、普段のそういうTPOにもよるけど...
Well, it depends on work and regular TPO, but...
え、でもなんか団長めっちゃいいなーって思った。
Eh, but Danchou thinks that's really nice!
なんか、それも好き...ではあるかなって。
I think that would also make me like them...
良いと思う。
I think it's good.
さっきのマシュマロの人もいたけどさ、ちいかわ1人で男性見たいけど、みたいに言ってたけど、
There was someone in the Marshmallows earlier saying they wanted to see Chiikawa alone as a guy...
いや、普通にそれって可愛ポイントだとラミ思うから、
I think that's honestly a really cute point,
なんかね、そういうマスコットとか、まあ物にもよるのかもしれない...
so having that kind of mascot or... well, maybe it depends on the item...
仕事場につけててから、いいなって思う。
I think having it even at the workplace is nice.
思いますね。
I agree.
思います。はい。話しかけるきっかけになりそうですね。
I agree. Yes. It seems like a good conversation starter.
そういう隙を作りつつ、でもお仕事頑張る君は素敵だよ、ということでね。
So while creating that kind of approachable gap, you working hard at your job is wonderful too.
はい！偉い！
Yes! Good job!
で、えー、締めたいと思います！すみません、ちょっと色々拾いたいのが色々あって、
And with that, let's wrap it up! Sorry, there were so many things we wanted to touch on...
配信時間ちょっと伸びちゃったんですけれども。今日はどうでしたか、ノエたん？
so the stream went a bit over time. How was it today, Noe-tan?
いや、もう出れて良かった！楽しかった！
Man, I'm so glad I could come! It was so much fun!
もうちょっとすごいさ、なかなかやっぱね、このガチトークだから、本当にガチな...
It was really, you know, because it's "Gachi Talk", really serious...
話色々聞けたりできたりして、
we got to talk about and hear so many genuine things,
あとマシュマロでもね、こういう悩んでる子がこんなにたくさんいるんだと思って。
and through the Marshmallows, we saw so many people worrying about these things.
さ、1点だけ、団長さ、脱毛のデメリット、言うの忘れてた。
Now, there's just one thing, Danchou. I forgot to mention the downside of hair removal.
ちょっとこれだけ伝えたい。全身脱毛による、の話なんだけど、
I just want to share this one thing. It's about full-body hair removal, but...
毛がないからさ、あの、泡立たなくなった。ボディソープが。
Because there's no hair, it stopped lathering. Body soap.
え、そんなことある？！
Wait, is that even a thing?!
Wait, does that really happen?!
団長ね、今までさ、何にもね、全身脱毛したことあるんだけど、
Danchou, I've had full-body hair removal before, but...
でも昔はさ、学生の時とかはさ、全然毛とかあったからさ、泡立ってたのよ、体。
back in the day, like when I was a student, I had body hair, so it would lather up on my body.
だからそのわざわざこうゴシゴシする、なんていうの、
So I didn't need to use those scrubby, what do you call it...
ボディソープを泡立てるバスタオルみたいの、あるじゃん？
...bath towels used to lather up body soap, right?
ああいうのを使わなくてよかったんだけど、
I didn't need to use those back then, but...
毛がなくなったら...
once the hair was gone...
つるつるでもうなんかさ、泡立たなくなっちゃった。
...it's so smooth that it just doesn't lather anymore.
毛で泡立ててたの？！
You were lathering with your hair?!
毛で泡立ててたんじゃないでしょ！
I wasn't using hair to lather it!
どんだけ生えてた？！
How much hair did you have?!
ボディソープの問題じゃないのかな？
Isn't it an issue with the body soap?
色々あるかもしれないけど、もしかしたらね、この脱毛考えてる人で、
There might be various reasons, but just in case anyone considering hair removal...
自分も毛で泡立ててたわ、みたいな人がいたら、
...is like "I lather using my body hair too,"...
そこはデメリットになるから気をつけた方がいいかなっていうので、そこだけね。
...that will become a downside, so you should be careful! That's all.
真剣な話かなって思ったけど、なんか「え？」ってなった。
I thought it was a serious topic, but then it was just like "Huh?!"
そんなことあるんだ。なるほどね。
I didn't know that happens. I see.
泡々になるさ、あの、なんて言うのあれ、モシュモシュモシュってなってるやつ使ってんだけど、こより。
I use that thing that makes lots of foam, what's it called, that squishy mesh ball thing.
あ、泡立てができるやつ？
Ah, the foaming sponge thing?
網々がフワフワフワーって集まってるやつ。
Where the mesh is all bunched up and fluffy.
あれ使えば、最初からブワーって泡立って、そのまま滑らせればオッケーになりそう。
If you use that, it foams up instantly, and you can just glide it over your skin.
ね、あれ、あれすごい。あれ革命よな。
Right, that thing is amazing. It's revolutionary.
だから、全身脱毛する人はそれを買って...
So, people getting full-body hair removal should buy that...
泡立たない？泡立てネット...
Doesn't it foam? Without a foaming net...
買わないと泡立たない。
it won't foam unless you buy one.
泡立... ま、そう、そうなのかな？
Foam... Well, I wonder if that's true?
まあまあまあ、そういう人もいるっていうことですね。
Well, it just means there are people like that too.
いる。まあ、ちょっと個人差はあると思いますけど。
There are. Though I'm sure it varies from person to person.
はい。泡立てネットおすすめなんで、ぜひ男子諸君もね、使っていただければ...
Yes. Foaming nets are great, so men, please feel free to use them...
使ってください。
Please use one.
え、でもどうなんだろうね？もちろん、すね毛とかさ、そういうのは...生えてなかったけど...
But I wonder? Of course, shin hair and such... not that they had any, but...
男の人ってすね毛とか腕毛とか濃い人いるじゃん？
some men have thick leg hair or arm hair, right?
逆にね、毛がある人が使うと、毛がすごい絡まっちゃうかもしれないから...
On the flip side, if someone hairy uses it, their hair might get really tangled in it...
ああ、泡立てネットが？
Ah, in the foaming net?
うん、泡立てネットに。
Yeah, in the foaming net.
毛が絡まることあんの？！え、泡立てネットに？！
Can hair get tangled in it?! Eh, in a foaming net?!
剛毛だと？！
If they're really hairy?!
剛毛で、こういっぱい生えてるとさ、ちょっと私想像したけど、こうやって...
If they're hairy and have a lot of it, I just imagined scrubbing like this...
なんかめっちゃ付きそうだから、その人はあの、これからはね...
and it seems like it'd get caught a lot, so for those people...
け、毛で... 毛で泡立てて...
Wi-with hair... lathering with their own hair...
「ねえよ」って言われてる！
"No way in hell," they're saying in chat!
ない？！嘘、ないか！
No way?! Really, no?!
分からない、想像で話しちゃった！
I don't know, I was just speaking from my imagination!
私、泡立てネットの小さな穴の1つ1つに毛が入っちゃうくらい絡まっちゃうかなって...
I just wondered if their hair would get tangled in each of those tiny net holes...
ボーボーぐらいの毛だったらなぁ、1回ちょっと... お試しでね、使ってみるといいかもしれないですね。
If someone is super bushy, maybe... giving it a try once as a test might be good.
そうですね。
That's true.
なるほど、なるほど。はい。
I see, I see. Yes.
楽しかった。お気遣いありがとうございます。
That was fun. Thank you for your consideration.
ま、楽しんでもらえて良かったです。ありがとうございます！
Well, I'm glad you enjoyed it! Thank you so much!
じゃあラミたん、今日はどうでしたか？
So Lamy-tan, how was it today?
え、今日はお二人の体を隅々まで洗えるっていうことが確定したので...
Well, today it was confirmed that I get to wash every inch of both of your bodies...
確定？！
Confirmed?!
確定したので、洗う順番とかね、何を使ったらいいのかというのを聞いておこうと思います。
Since it's confirmed, I'll make sure to ask in advance about the washing order and what to use.
ありがとうございます。待って、それどうしよう？あ、はい。
Thank you. Wait, what should we do about that? Ah, yes.
え、こよは？こよは？
Eh, what about Koyo? What about Koyo?
えっ、こよりはちょっと今のラミたんので本当に洗われることがあるのだろうかと、男子小学生の気分になっているんですけど...
Um, after hearing Lamy-tan just now, Koyori is feeling like an elementary school boy wondering if she's really going to wash me...
あるかもよ。
It might happen.
本当かも、ってちょっと今緊張してしまっているんですけど。
Thinking it might actually happen, I'm getting a little nervous right now.
でもやっぱりゲストがいると、ラミこよとまた別の価値観だったりとか、出てこない発想とかが出てきて...
But having a guest really brings out different values and fresh perspectives we wouldn't have thought of...
ノエたんがとにかく優しいし...
Noe-tan is just so kind...
いやいやいや... / 優しいね。
No, no, no... / She really is.
包容力。
So embracing.
ね！結局何でも受け止めてくれそうだなっていうので、なんかより好きになってしまいました。
Right! It feels like she'd accept anything, so I ended up loving her even more.
いや嬉しい！団長も本当さ、このガチトーク出たかったから、今回ゲストに出れて嬉しいんだけど...
I'm so happy! Honestly, Dancho really wanted to appear on Gachi Talk, so I'm thrilled to be a guest today, but...
確かにこよちゃんが冒頭で言ってた、結構人を選んでしまうのではないか、みたいな言ってたけど...
Koyori-chan did mention at the beginning that this show might not be for everyone...
団長はね、本当に今後もこのガチトーク続いていって、このラインがOKなホロメンとかも出ていって...
But Dancho really hopes Gachi Talk continues on, and Holo members who are fine with this line can come on...
価値観とか色々聞けたらな、嬉しいなと思っておりますので。
so we can hear about all their different values and thoughts.
優しいな〜。
So sweet~
ちなみに、もういつでも暇なんで、もし集まらなかったら、いつでも駆り出して永遠にゲストとか、はい、ありますのでね。
By the way, I'm always free, so if you ever can't find a guest, feel free to draft me as an eternal guest anytime!
無限ゲストだ。
An infinite guest.
すのつのノエルになる可能性がありますね。
It might become "Su-no-Tsu-Noel"!
なるね！お願いいたしま〜す。
It would! Please have me~
え、嬉しい！女子が一人増えると色んな価値観があるんだなと思って、今日もすごく楽しかったです。ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy! Having one more girl shows how diverse our values can be, so today was super fun. Thank you so much!
ありがとう。/ またぜひノエたんも遊びに来てください！
Thank you. / Please come hang out again, Noe-tan!
はーい！遊びに来まーす！
Okay! I'd love to!
感想は #すのつの女子トーク でぜひハッシュタグで呟いてくれると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
We'd love it if you shared your thoughts with the hashtag #すのつの女子トーク. Please do!
お願いしまーす！
Please do!
ということで夜遅くまでありがとうございました！それでは、おつガチトークでいきますか！
So, thank you so much for staying up late with us! Shall we wrap up with "Otsu Gachi Talk"?!
はい！ / 締めます！せーの！
Yes! / Let's finish! Ready, set...
おつガチトーク！
Otsu Gachi Talk!
おやすみなさーい！
Good night~!
わーお わーおだ 叫んじゃえ
Sing it out, shout out "Wao, wao!"
泣いて 鳴いて 愛して 尻尾振って
Cry, howl, love, and wag your tail
見てくれてありがとう！ / わーお わーおだ 叫んじゃえ
Thanks for watching! / Sing it out, shout out "Wao, wao!"
叫んじゃえ
Shout it out!
だめなぼくを どうか覚えておいて
Please remember me, flawed as I am
目指すキラキラも きっとぼく次第だ
That shining goal surely depends on me
ビター？ ギブアップなんて言わないんだ
Bitter? I'm not gonna say I give up
加速メラメラで ぶっちぎる次第です
Accelerating full-throttle, I'll pull way ahead
はぐれずに希望へ大暴走
Charging toward hope without getting lost
きみの心 チクッとしちゃって
Giving your heart a little sting
また会いに来てね！
Come see me again, okay?
いいじゃん ハッピーじゃん
Isn't it great? It's so happy!